什么?
What?
希望渺茫?
A long shot?
这个比赛吗?
This race?
不能错过?
Can't miss?
谢谢你,宝贝。
Thanks, baby.
从零用现金中拿出两根胡萝卜。
Take two carrots out of petty cash.
我和你核对一下。
I'll check with you.
来吧，孩子。
Come on, kid.
我们走吧。
Let's go.
为什么?
Why?
我在做什么?
What am I doing?
兜售了。
Touting again.
吹捧吗?
Touting?
他吗?
Him?
听着，孩子。
Now, listen, kid.
我们看到你用了很多疯狂的方法。
We've seen you use some pretty wild schemes.
为什么?
Why?
这匹马碰巧喜欢吃柠檬汁，这是一种罪过吗?
Is it a crime this horse happens to have A sweet tooth for lemon drops?
是啊，但你用这个对付那些疯狂的赛马玩家，他们会认为这匹马是在给你小费。
Yeah, but you're using this on these crazy horse players, They'll think the horse is giving you a tip.
你知道，我知道，这匹马也知道。
Well, you know it and I know it and the horse knows it.
但在法庭上听起来会很奇怪。
But it'll sound very peculiar in court.
你就出格一次，小子。
Just step out of line once, Kid.
手铐已经准备好了。
The handcuffs are ready.
别再烦我了，好吗?
Lay off me, will you?
如果幸运的话，我会给你买加水的冰块。
And if I get lucky, I'll buy you some ice with waters.
回想一下，就在上周四，我接受了他的一条建议。
To think just last Thursday, I went for one of his tips.
你也吗?
You, too?
我告诉你，乔治，我预感到肉馅饼会出事。
I tell you, George, I've got a hunch on Mince Pie.
记得那次你吃了那个女人的派，第二天你就不能去上班了，因为你生病了?
Remember that time you ate that woman's pie, And you couldn't go to work the next day because you were sick?
办公室被闪电击中了。
And the office was struck by lightning.
艾伦，那匹马不会因为名字叫肉馅饼就跑得更快的。
Ellen, that horse isn't going to run any faster Just because its name is Mince Pie.
肉馅饼三岁时表现不错。
Mince Pie is a pretty good three-year-old.
会赢得很多比赛。
Going to win a lot of races.
也就是说，如果它的腿康复了。
That is, if its leg gets well.
你……你觉得他的腿有问题吗?
You... you think there's something wrong with his leg?
觉得呢?
Think?
我是田径兽医。
I'm the track vet.
这是"阴道前"感染在"联邦"区域，这…哦，韧带发炎了。
It's a "precastinary" infection of the "fedasorial" area, Which... oh, inflamed ligaments.
想象一下，让一条坏腿的马去比赛。
Imagine allowing a horse to race with a bad leg.
一半的马都该坐轮椅。
Half of these horses should be in wheelchairs.
这是他们抢栏杆的唯一原因，这让他们有了依靠。
It's the only reason they fight for the rail, It gives them something to lean on.
你相信吗，比赛中只有一匹健康的马?
Would you believe it, there's only one Sound horse in the race?
医生吗?
Doctor?
医生。
Doctor.
嗯嗯?
Mm-hm?
你说只有一匹马没病。
You said there was only one horse that wasn't sick.
医生，请问是哪一个?
Please, Doc, which one?
所有的信息都是机密的，知道吗?
All that information is confidential, you know?
有点像医生和病人之间的关系。
Sort of between doctor and patient.
我们不会告诉任何人。
We wouldn't tell anybody.
你可以和我们分享你的秘密。
You could share your secret with us.
我们会和你分享我们的奖金。
And we'd share our winnings with you.
哦不，求你了，求你了。
Oh no, please, please.
那是不道德的。
That would be unethical.
不过，如果比赛结束后，你愿意为诊所捐点东西吗?
However, if after the race, you'd Like to donate something to the clinic?
我们太拥挤了，每张床上都有两匹马。
We're so overcrowded, we have two horses in every bed.
哦，当然，我们会的。
Oh, certainly, we will.
哪匹马感觉不错?
Uh, which horse feels well?
如果我是个赌徒，我会认为S-I-X是个非常幸运的数字。
Well, if I were a betting man, I'd Consider S-I-X a very lucky number.
骶髂关节……嘘。
S-I... Shh.
好了，安静。
All right, shush.
——S-I-X。-那是伦巴舞。
- S-I-X. - That's Rhumba Dancer.
来吧，艾伦。
Come on, Ellen.
谢谢你，医生。
Thank you, Doctor.
你为你的职业增光。
You're a credit to your profession.
哦，没什么。
Oh, ho, it's nothing.
不好意思。
Uh, excuse me.
请原谅我这么挤进来，我大老远从芝加哥飞过来就是为了看我哥哥的比赛。
Pardon me for crowding in, but I flew all the way from Chicago To see my brother ride this race.
我第一次看到他骑冠军。
First time I get to see him ride a winner.
他哥哥是个骑师。
His brother's a jockey.
有趣的事情。
Funny thing.
妈妈一直以为他会是个子高的那个。
Mom always thought he was going to be the tall one.
你怎么知道你哥哥会赢?
How do you know your brother's going to win?
有很多方法可以修好，除非他们想把东西弄歪。
Lots of ways it's fixed, unless they Try to pull something crooked.
有时候，马也会自己做交易。
Sometimes, the horses make their own deals, too, you know.
好吧，你弟弟叫什么名字?
Uh, well, uh, what's your brother's name?
我们也要为他加油。
We'd like to cheer for him, too.
如果你知道，你就知道是哪匹马了。
If you knew that, you'd know which horse.
哦，你不会后悔的。
Oh, you won't be sorry.
比赛结束后我会照顾你的。
I'll take care of you after the race.
一大块。
A big chunk.
哦。
Oh.
我不是那么在乎钱。
Well, I don't care about the money so much.
毕竟，你们看起来确实像正派人。
After all, you do look like decent people.
数字是S-E-V-E-N。
The number is S-E-V-E-N.
S-E-V-E-N。那是铁棒。
S-E-V-E-N. That's Iron Bar.
我们真高兴能遇到你。
Oh, we're so glad we happened to meet you.
你相信吗?
Would you believe it?
这是我们今天赢的第一场比赛。
This is the first race we've won today.
好吧,然后……哦,有…这是你哥哥。
Well, then... Oh, there... there's your brother now.
嗯?
Hm?
哦，嗨，杰瑞!
Oh, hi, Jerry!
爸爸妈妈向你问好。
Mom and Dad send their love.
祝你好运，孩子!
Lots of luck, kid!
看到他怎么假装不认识我了吗?
See how he pretends not to know me?
最聪明的小操作员。
Smartest little operator around.
我告诉你，先生，我知道我们在圣诞节比赛。
I tell you, sir, I know we race Christmas Day.
听着，孩子，我得确定。
Look, sonny, I got to be sure.
现在，帮我去问问威尔金森法官。
Now, go ask Judge Wilkinson for me.
嗯嗯。
Mm-hm.
他们还在印美元，是吧?
They're still printing dollars, huh?
哦，你说什么，女士?
Oh, I beg your pardon, ma'am?
你们都在跟我说话?
Y'all addressing me?
好吧，亲爱的孩子，你是不是把这5美元掉在地上了?
Well, honey child, Did y'all just dropped this $5 bill?
哦,我……我不可能。
Oh, I... I couldn't have.
我的都是百位。
Mine are all hundreds.
是的，我的也是。
Yeah, mine, too.
它一定是某个北方佬的。
It must belong to some Yankee.
你们一定很幸运，因为你们很漂亮。
Well, y'all must be as lucky as you are beautiful.
我的绅士朋友把这一切都押在了铁棒上。
My gentleman friend is betting all this on Iron Bar.
铁酒吧?
Iron Bar?
好吧，玉米饼和猪肠!
Well, corn my pone and chit my chitlins!
我本来打算自己在那匹马身上留下一个漂亮的身材，直到我叔叔告诉我比赛已经安排好了。
I was going to drop a handsome figure on that animal Myself until my uncle told me the race was fixed.
你的叔叔吗?
Your uncle?
是的。
Yeah.
那是威尔金森法官。
Well, that's Judge Wilkinson.
他是赛马俱乐部的头牌，也是终点线的主审。
He's the president of the Turf Club, And also, the head judge of the finish line.
我现在只是在等他点头。
I'm just waiting now for him to give me the nod.
当然，他是在调查。
He's investigating, of course.
我的，首席裁判!
My, head judge!
这是他。
That's him.
有漂亮女孩的那个。
The one with the pretty girl.
他给了我1美元问你圣诞节那天我们是否比赛。
He gives me $1 to ask you if we race on Christmas Day.
他不相信我的话。
He won't take my word for it.
一定是个游客。
Must be a tourist.
好吧，如果比赛注定铁棒会输，你必须知道谁会赢。
Well, if the race is fixed for Iron Bar to lose, You must know who's going to win.
是啊，但我不能泄露那样的信息。
Yeah, but I couldn't divulge information Like that.
我发过誓要保守秘密。
I've been sworn to secrecy.
我以南方真正绅士的身份发誓。
I gave my word as a true gentleman of the South.
我对着一堆黑眼豌豆和蜜饯山药发誓。
I swore on a stack of black eyed peas and candied yams.
这封邮件已被绑定。
This message had been binded.
这里有两千现金。
There's two thousand cash-money here.
我的绅士朋友会在比赛结束后好好照顾你的。
My gentleman friend would take good care of you After the race.
好吧，祝福你的心，亲爱的孩子。
Well, bless your heart, honey child.
号码是E-I-G-H，你们都是T。
Uh, the number is, uh, E-I-G-H, y'all, T.
你是说闪电侠?
You mean Lightning Streak?
没有其他。
None other.
谢谢你，先生。
Thank you, sir.
比赛结束后，我们在生菜柜台见。
Uh, after the race, I'll meet you at the lettuce counter.
我们会解决的。
We'll settle up.
你们理解。
Y'all understand.
闪电!
Lightning Streak!
嘿,小子。
Hey, kid.
你要大展拳脚了吗?
You getting on the big time?
我在扩大我的生意。
I'm expanding my business.
我要扩展到100美元的窗口。
I'm branching into the hundred-dollar window.
你拿到那些战利品了吗?
Did you get a load of that loot?
有个西红柿和她自己的卷心菜块。
There's a tomato with her own cabbage patch.
两个G的!
Two G's!
嗯嗯。
Mm-hm.
噢!
Ow!
你想要什么?
What do you expect?
穆斯·莫兰总是下大赌注。
Moose Moran always bets heavy.
驼鹿莫兰吗?
Moose Moran?
你是说那个娃娃是穆斯·莫兰的?
You mean that doll belongs to Moose Moran?
你不知道?
You didn't know it?
嘿，你最好确定你给了他一个赢家。
Hey, you better be sure you gave him a winner.
一个胜利者吗?
A winner?
我分不清一匹马和另一匹马。
I don't know one horse from another.
我最好抓住她，告诉她手术结束了，让她换电话号码。说…
I better grab her and tell her the fix is off, have her change Her number. Say...
他们走了!
There they go!
铁棒领先了。
It's Iron Bar taking the lead.
闪电。
Lightning Streak.
你在哪里?
Where are you?
你想双手沾上我的血。
You want my blood on your hands.
闪电!
Lightning!
闪电闪电以11比7领先杆位。
Lightning Streak is 11 to 7 to pole.
爸爸，我遇到了最好的男人。
Daddy, I met the nicest man.
我给了你两千块赌铁棒。
I gave you two grand to bet on Iron Bar.
我知道，但铁棒没机会了。
I know, but Iron Bar doesn't have a chance.
那个好人告诉我谁将赢得这场比赛。
The nice man told me who all's going to win the race.
背部拉伸结束，铁棒拉长。
End of the back stretch, Iron Bar lengthening out.
这个好人吃柠檬糖了吗?
Was this nice man eating lemon drops?
你们都认识那个好人吗?
Y'all know the nice man?
嗯嗯。
Mm-hm.
我跟那个好人说了比赛结束后给他点东西。
I told the nice man y'all give him something after the race.
是的。
Yes.
比赛结束后，我们会给这位好人一些东西。
We'll give the nice man something after the race.
铁棒现在领先5-7个长度。
Iron Bar now leading 5-7 lengths.
“鞍后”现在是第二长的。
Saddle Queen is now second in length.
还有闪电条纹。
And Lightning Streak.
孩子，铁棒带着它跑了。
Kid, Iron Bar is running away with it.
呆在那里，铁棍。
Stay there, Iron Bar.
呆在那儿!
Stay there!
你想害死我?
You want to get me killed?
来吧，闪电侠!
Come on, Lightning Streak!
来吧!
Come on!
但你告诉我们铁棒。
But you told us Iron Bar.
你不记得了吗?
Don't you remember?
我们不想让任何人知道我们参与了这件事。
We don't want anyone to know we're in on it.
来吧，闪电侠!
Come on, Lightning Streak!
来吧，闪电侠。
Come on, Lightning Streak.
最后冲刺，铁棒保持领先。
Final stretch, Iron Bar holding his lead.
多么精彩的比赛!
What a race!
看那匹马跑!
Look at that horse run!
如果你觉得他能跑，看这个!
If you think he can run, watch this!
铁棒轻松获胜。
And it's Iron Bar, the winner, easily.
还有闪电条纹。
And Lightning Streak.
但这个好人确信闪电条纹会赢。
But the nice man was sure Lightning Streak Was going to win.
慕斯生气了吗?
Is Moose angry?
喂，你刚才说得对。
Say, you were right before.
我在兜售那匹马。
I was touting that horse.
我承认。
I admit it.
我承认!
I confess!
我整个下午都在卖马。
I've been touting horses all afternoon.
把我关进监狱。
Put me in jail.
请把我关进监狱!
Please put me in jail!
你在开玩笑吗?
Are you kidding?
这是什么新把戏啊?
What kind of a new racket is this?
我是美国公民。
Well, I'm a citizen.
我交税。
I pay taxes.
我有权被关进监狱。
I got a right to be put in jail.
给我耳光!
Slap them on me!
你又想把我们变成笨蛋吗?
Are you trying to make chumps out of us again?
不，我只是不小心吹捧了慕斯·莫兰。
No, I just touted Moose Moran by mistake.
我吹捧他是赢家。
I touted him off a winner.
他会杀了我的。
He'll kill me.
你知道，我们也知道慕斯·莫兰也知道。
Well, you know it and we know it and Moose Moran knows this.
但在法庭上听起来很奇怪。
But it would sound very peculiar in court.
我会让他们起草的。
I'll have them draft it.
我的钥匙呢?
My key?
信贷经理想和你谈谈。
The credit manager wants to talk to you.
你不想和信贷经理谈谈吗?
Do you not want to talk to the credit manager?
-你想和慕斯谈谈。-不，不。
- You want to talk to Moose. - No, no.
我…我不想和他们任何一个说话。
I... I don't want to talk to either one of them.
我…慕斯想请你和他喝一杯。
I... Well, Moose wants you to have a drink with him.
不，我不渴。
No, I'm not thirsty.
慕斯说你渴了。
Moose said you're thirsty.
不,我……我改天再约。
No, I... I'll take a rain check.
慕斯喜欢你。
Moose likes you.
是啊，我也喜欢他。
Yeah, I'm fond of him, too.
我们出去吧。
Let's go outside.
是的。不,伙计们。
Yeah. No, fellas.
我已经决定了!
I've made up my mind!
我们走吧。
Let's go.
我想我会晚一点回来的!
I'll be back later, I think!
我将……哈哈。
I'll be... ha-ha.
你儿子说你想和我喝一杯真有趣。
Funny when your boys said you wanted to have a drink with me.
我还以为他们在开玩笑呢。
I thought they were kidding.
哈哈。
Ha-ha.
谢谢你,斯佳丽。
Thanks, Scarlett.
慕斯，你是个可靠的公民，能承受这样的损失。
Moose, you're a real solid citizen, Taking your loss like this.
我为什么要为了一万块得高血压?
Why should I get high blood pressure for about ten grand?
是的，我就是这么说的。
Yeah, that's what I say.
不值得……十大吗?
It's not worth... ten grand?
我以为你只丢了两个?
I thought you only lost two?
是的，但是马赢了。
Yeah, but the horse won.
他们会付给我一万美元的。
They would have paid me ten grand.
来吧，我带你四处看看。
Come on, I'll show you around.
这样的布局，即使是一万美金也不便宜吧?
Say, with a layout like this, even ten grand Must be bird feed, huh?
是的。
Yeah.
这里有个小洞。
Over here is a sort of den.
把它修理得很特别。
Had it fixed up special.
噢!
Ow!
我的天啊!
Oh, my god!
的帮助。
Help.
没关系。
It's all right.
看一看。
Have a look.
噢!
Ow!
啊!
Ugh!
噢。
Ow.
也许他没有钻石。
Maybe he ain't got the diamond.
慕斯认为是他在豪华轿车里吞下的。
Moose thinks he swallowed it when We had him in the limousine.
准备好了,山姆?
Ready, Sam?
噢!
Ow!
怎么了，孩子?
What's the matter, Kid?
你看起来有点不舒服。
You look kind of sick.
不，不，每年这个时候我都会变绿。
No, no, uh, I always turn green this time of the year.
哦!
Ohh!
也许你最好坐下来。
Maybe you'd better sit down.
至少。
At least.
啊呀!
Aargh!
不，别说了，我来说吧。
No, don't I'll talk.
我要说话。
I'll talk.
啊。
Ahh.
我没有吞下钻石。
I didn't swallow the diamond.
它在我的鞋里…在鞋跟。
It's in my shoe... in the heel.
既然你感觉好多了，我们来谈谈你欠我的一万块钱吧。
Now, that you're feeling better, Let's talk about the ten grand you owe me.
哦，但是你说…不，不是钱的问题。
Oh, but you said... No, it's not the money.
我只是不想让那些聪明人嘲笑我。
I just don't like to have all the smart guys get The laugh on me.
这是钻石，慕斯。
Here's the diamond, Moose.
小子，我想让你认识一下外科医生山姆。
Oh, Kid, I'd like you to know Sam the Surgeon.
山姆，这是柠檬小子。
Sam, this is the Lemon Drop Kid.
请原谅我的手套。
Pardon the glove.
你是真正的医生吗?
Are you a genuine doctor?
实际上。
Practically.
如果我不是高三的时候丢了个正考，我早就毕业了。
Would have graduated if I didn't drop A forward pass in my senior year.
我认识的第一个医生把他取出来的东西扔掉了。
First doctor I ever met keeps what He takes out and throws the patient away.
好吧，我要走了。
Well, I'll be going.
哦，哦，看，慕斯，我只有15美分和一盒柠檬糖。
Oops, oh, look, Moose, all I got is fifteen cents and a box of lemon drops.
你有吗?
You have one?
慕斯，我没有一万块钱。
Moose, I haven't got ten grand.
我身上没带，体内也没带。
I haven't got it on me or in me.
想把我变成傻瓜是很痛苦的。
Trying to make me a sucker can be very painful.
我们要为他做手术准备吗?
Shall we prepare him for surgery?
等等，慕斯。
Oh, now, wait, Moose.
听着，我会拿到一万美元的。
Look, I'll get the ten grand.
我将……"离圣诞节只有23天购物了"
I'll... hey, "Only 23 shopping days till Christmas."
要是我能活到圣诞节就好了。
If I only had till Christmas.
你从哪儿弄来一万块钱?
Where would you get ten grand?
如果我能去纽约，我就会有更多的机会。
Well, I'll have more of a chance If I could get to New York.
我在百老汇有很多朋友。
I've got a lot of friends on Broadway.
一个名字。
Name one.
嗯，有，呃，还有，呃…呃，他还没出来。
Well, there's, uh, and then there's, Uh... uh, he's not out yet.
嗯，好吧，他们不是朋友。
And the, eh, OK, so they're not friends.
我告诉你，我还能筹到钱。
I tell you, I can still raise the money.
通过兜售两美元的马匹玩家?
By touting two-dollar horse players?
不，我会想办法的。
No, I'll find a way.
不管山姆现在杀了我还是圣诞节前不打开我，对你来说都一样。
It's all the same to you whether Sam kills me Now or doesn't open me till Christmas.
如果我拿到钱，你就能提前一万。
And if I get the money, you are ten grand ahead.
你看，慕斯?
You see, Moose?
拿一万美金对你来说很有趣。
Picking up ten grand will be fun for you.
这样杀了我，太草率了。
And killing me this way, it'd be so sloppy.
慕斯，当然，我一直都想成为城里的男人，但不是小打小闹，你知道。
Moose, sure, I've always wanted to be a man about town, But not in little chunks, you see.
作为，呃，呃…死了，我就把一万记下来。
As, uh, uh... Dead, I write ten thousand off the books.
还活着，可能是线人。
Alive, possible asset.
好的，我会在纽约过圣诞节。
OK, I'll be in New York for Christmas.
我想和我的妻子和孩子一起度过。
I want to spend it with my wife and kids.
他们在寄宿学校。
They're in boarding school.
如果他跑了怎么办?
What if he runs away?
我们会找到他的。
We'll find him.
是啊，我听说你能找到这么好的人，在你找到他们之后，没人能找到他们。
Yeah, I hear you find people so good that after you find them, Nobody else can find them.
孩子，我在长岛有个赌场。
Kid, I got some property in Long Island, a casino.
哦，我知道那个地方。
Oh, I know the place.
他们关闭了它进行维修。
They closed it down for repairs.
轮盘赌开始有了回报。
The roulette wheel started paying off.
我要到北方来卖它。
I'm coming North to peddle it.
平安夜你要给我钱。
You have the money for me Christmas Eve.
或者圣诞节的早晨，你会发现你的头在袜子里。
Or Christmas morning, you'll find your head In your stocking.
我的头在袜子里?
My head in my stocking?
好吧，那不是po…哦,哦。
Well, that's not po... oh, oh.
谢谢你陪我度过一个愉快的夜晚。
Thanks for a nice evening.
圣诞快乐!
Merry Christmas!
你很幸运，我来了。
Lucky thing for you, I came along.
谢谢你，先生。
Thank you, sir.
你为什么不看路呢?
Why don't you watch where you're going?
我本想吹喇叭的，但它冻住了。
I would have blown my horn, but it's frozen.
你看，这样的天气，我的报纸销量一直不太好。
You see, the way the weather is, My paper sales have been a way off.
但我会想办法帮你弄到的。
But I'll get it for you some way.
我有朋友在附近。
I got friends about.
内莉!
Nellie!
我…就我所知，今天是内莉·星期四!
I... As I practically live and breathe, it's Nellie Thursday!
孩子!
Kid!
卖冰淇淋?
Selling ice cream?
冰淇淋。
Ice creams.
内尔还是老样子。
Same old Nell.
天啊，见到你真高兴。
Boy, am I glad to see you.
哦，我很高兴见到你。
Oh, and am I glad to see you.
你来得正是时候，小子。
You're just in time, Kid.
这是佛罗里达最新的东西…比基尼毛衣。
It's the newest thing in Florida... the bikini sweater.
制作它的女孩给我签了名。
The gal that made it autographed it for me.
汪,汪。
Woof, woof.
孩子，我欠伊根先生钱。
Kid, I owe Mr. Egan some money.
你还记得你欠我的20美元吗?
You remember that twenty dollars you owe me?
什么，可怜的20美元?
What, a measly twenty dollars?
我不仅记得这20，我还会把它还上，然后乘以20。
And I not only remember the twenty, I'm gonna pay it back and multiply it by twenty.
够她付我四个月的房租了，还有一些。
That'll take care of the four months' rent she owes me, And then some.
你别插手。
You keep out of this.
听着，内莉，借我十块钱，好吗?
Listen, Nellie, lend me ten dollars, will you?
这样我就能把冬天的衣服拿回来了?
So I can get my winter clothes out of hock?
我不能穿成这样去雪莉和丽兹见我的朋友。
I can't go see my friends at the Sherry And the Ritz looking like this.
他们会问我一些我不知道答案的问题。
They'd ask me questions for which I'm out of answers.
孩子，你知道你在丽兹没有朋友。
Kid, you know you have not any friends at the Ritz.
内莉，你怎么能这么说?
Nellie, how can you say that?
你知道的。
You know I have.
为什么有…手不对。
Why there's... uh, wrong hand.
嗯，有，呃，呃…别担心，我会把钱还给你的。
Well, there's, uh, uh... don't worry, I'll give you the money back.
6点前拿到。
Get it by 6 o'clock.
这样你就有时间占领孤儿院了。
That'll give you time to dispossess an orphanage.
你知道吗，内莉，如果我有内裤，我会把我身上的衬衫都给你。
You know, Nellie, I'd give you the shirt off my back If I had any underwear on.
当然,孩子。
Sure, Kid.
我知道。
I know that.
不只是我。
It's not just for me.
是给我丈夫的。
It's for my husband.
你还记得我丈夫亨利吗?
You remember my husband, Henry?
谁不喜欢呢?
Well, who doesn't?
31年的新新班。
Sing Sing Class of '31.
这是业界最棒的保险箱小撬。
Greatest little safe cracker in the business.
亨利二十年后就要假释了。
Henry's getting paroled after twenty years.
他平安夜出狱。
He gets out Christmas Eve.
平安夜出去?
Gets out Christmas Eve?
圣诞夜。
Christmas Eve.
我可能见不到他了。
I may not be around to see him.
但我会的，这样我就可以告诉他我们没地方住了。
But I will, so I can tell him how we got no place to stay.
是啊，那你和亨利要搬去的那个老人院呢?
Yeah, well, what happened to that old folks' home That you and Henry were moving in?
是的，阳光之家。
Yes, Sunshine Home, huh.
他们拒绝了我的申请…都是为了亨利。
Well, they turned down my application... All on account of Henry.
他们不会收有前科的人。
They won't take an ex-convict.
下次探访日，我会告诉亨利待在原地不动。
Come next visiting day, I'm going To tell Henry to stay right where he is.
至少，那里是暖和的。
At least, it's warm up there.
即。
Brr.
论文!
Papers!
后期文件!
Late files!
坚持住，内莉。
Stay with it, Nellie.
振作起来。
Keep your chins up.
总会有办法的。
Something will work out.
嗯，也许是这样。
Well, maybe so.
我遇到过比这更糟糕的困境。
I've been in worst jams than this.
至少，你不再孤单了。
At least, you're not alone anymore, anyway.
回头见。
I'll see you.
图特·肖尔、波莉·特里、d·科拉、潘乔·欧·德怀尔、格罗弗·威廉、戈德堡、托尼·伯克……巴克斯特Brainey。
Toot Shore, Polly Terry, D. Cora, Pancho O'Dwyer, Grover William, Goldberg, Tony Burke... Brainey Baxter.
啊，她还住在这里。
Ah, she still lives here.
即。
Brr.
你们得靠自己了，伙计们。
You're on your own, fellas.
《银河系漫游指南》。
Hitchhiker.
嗯，嗯，嗯，嗯，嗯。
Rrrh, mm, hmm, hmm, hmm.
嗯,嗯。
Hmm, hmm.
我以前从没见过它开花。
I never saw it bloom before.
啊，还能用。
Ah, still works.
如果你必须死，那是什么罪啊。
What a crime if you had to die.
哦，一个花花公子。
Oh, a dandy.
人力资源管理。
Hrm.
我讨厌离开你，但这是命运!
I hate to leave you, but that's fate!
哦，你这个娃娃，你!
Oh, you doll, you!
Brainey !
Brainey!
布雷尼，你这个漂亮的娃娃，你!
Brainey, you gorgeous doll, you!
你迟到了，小子。
You're late, Kid.
我一到城里就过来了。
Oh, I came over as soon as I hit town.
迟了六个月。
Six months late.
你拿走了我的外套。
You left with my coat.
你本来要帮我当掉的。
You were going to pawn it for me.
我在等你回来。
I waited for you to come back.
是这样的。
Well, it's like this.
我正拿着你的钱回来。
I was on my way back with your money right in my hand.
突然，我听说佛罗里达有一笔大生意。
All at once, I heard about a big deal in Florida.
我想你在佛罗里达不需要皮大衣。
Well, I figured you won't need a fur coat in Florida.
你去了佛罗里达，我留在这里。
You went to Florida, I stayed here.
哦,Brainey。
Oh, Brainey.
用这件大衣偿还我欠你的钱是轻而易举的事。
Squaring the money I owe you in the coat is a cinch.
我刚在迈阿密发了财。
I just struck it rich in Miami.
嗯，你看起来很像。
Mm, you look it.
哦，你不明白。
Oh, you don't understand.
我和一些有钱的朋友在赛马场，我想到了我爱的女人…也就是你，布莱尼·巴克斯特。
I'm out at the racetrack with some wealthy friends, And I get to thinking about the woman I love... meaning you, Brainey Baxter.
当然，我不会等着改变。
Naturally, I don't wait to change.
我赶了第一班飞机回家。
I grabbed the first plane home.
我的行李在路上。
My luggage is on the way.
如果迈阿密很胖，你怎么走得这么急?
If Miami is fat, how come you left in such a hurry?
哦，呃，有一匹马叫婚礼仪式…赢得第二场比赛。
Oh, uh, there's a horse named Wedding Ceremony... wins the second race.
婚礼，这是预感。
Wedding Ceremony, that's a hunch.
除了你和我，谁都有可能。
It could mean nobody but you and I.
现在，看，小子。
Now, look, Kid.
我记得你是怎么操作的。
I remember how you operate.
没有限制。
No holds barred.
现在，我们不要谈论婚礼除非你是诚实的。
Now, let's not talk about a wedding ceremony Unless you're on the level.
我不怪你不信任我，布雷尼。
Oh, I don't blame you for not trusting me, Brainey.
有时候我不相信自己。
Sometimes I have days when I don't trust me.
但为了配得上你，我愿意做任何事。
But I'll do anything to be worthy of you.
说不定还能找到工作。
Might even get a job.
婚礼和工作?
A wedding ceremony and a job?
这是今年最伟大的一次冒险。
That's the greatest long shot parlay of the year.
是的。
Yeah.
我真希望我没把钱包落在我的新羊绒裤子里。
I just wish I hadn't left my wallet in my new cashmere Slacks.
等我的衣服一到，我就带十块钱去拿驾照。
As soon as my clothes arrive, I'll take ten bucks and go right down And get a license.
这就告诉你了。
That'll show you.
我有十块钱。
I've get ten bucks.
是吗?
Yeah?
我说你是在虚张声势，小子。
I'm calling your bluff, Kid.
我们现在就能拿到执照。
We can get the license right now.
哦,娃娃!
Oh, doll!
我马上去执照局。
I'll be right down to the license bureau.
哦,等等!
Oh, wait!
我要穿什么东西了。
I'll slip into something.
哦，不要，不要。
Oh, don't, no.
你不需要一起去。
No need you going along.
你留在这里，把这里收拾好。
You stay here and fix up this place.
记住，这是我们的蜜月小屋。
Remember, this is our honeymoon cottage.
有很多香槟和五彩纸屑，是吧?
Get a lot of champagne and confetti, huh?
就站在那里，就像这样。
And just stand there, just like that.
漂亮!
Beautiful!
一路走到市区，我想记住你的微笑。
All the way downtown, I want to remember you smiling.
但我们都得去领执照。
But we both have to appear for a license.
嘿，小子，等等!
Hey, Kid, wait!
我的十块钱。
My ten bucks.
他又这样做了。
He did it again.
团聚,伙计们。
Reunion, fellas.
Hrrrm。
Hrrrm.
糊，糊，糊，糊!
Mush, mush, mush, mush!
查理先生，根据我们的数据，你欠31400美元。
Mr. Charlie, according to our figures, You owe the government $31,400.
你是说，我付的保护费不能扣减吗?
You mean to say, all that dough I Paid for protection isn't deductible?
那笔钱只是…你想要什么?
Well, that money is just... what do you want?
嗯，我只是路过。
Well, I was just passing by.
我想去看看我的老朋友牛津·查理。
Thought I'd drop in to see my old pal Oxford Charlie.
你好吗?
How are you?
你的脚怎么样了?
How's your feet?
他们要杀了我。
They're killing me.
你来这儿干什么?给予还是得到?
What are you here for... Giving or getting?
查理，我要跟你分一杯羹。
Oh, Charlie, I'm cutting you in on a solid gold deal.
你可以用你那份利润穿貂皮牛津鞋了。
You'd be able to wear ermine oxfords With your share of the profits.
你只要拿出一万现金就行了。
All you have to put up is ten grand in cash.
这就够了。
That's enough.
把面包屑扔出去。
Throw the crumb out.
但你只需要种上区区一万美元，就能收获一大笔钱!
But all you have to do is plant a measly ten grand, And you harvest a fortune!
把他扔出去。
Throw him out.
我所得税的麻烦还不够多吗?
Ain't I got enough trouble with income tax?
哦，但是，查理!
Oh, but, Charlie!
牛津，我欠穆斯·莫兰一万美元。
Listen, Oxford, I owe Moose Moran ten grand.
要么他在圣诞夜收到，要么我在圣诞节早上收到。
Either he gets it Christmas Eve or I get it Christmas morning.
把钱借给我，好吗?
Lend me the dough, will you?
你知道慕斯会做什么。
You know what Moose will do.
我就会穿着水泥泳衣被扔进河里。
I'll wind up in the river with a cement bathing suit.
我来供应水泥。
I'll supply the cement.
出去!
Out!
哦，但是，查理，我…查……我留下我的电话号码以防你改变主意?
Oh, but, Charlie, I... Cha... I'll leave my phone number In case you change your mind, huh?
对不起，哦!
I'm sorry, oh!
共产主义!
Communist!
帮助有需要的人!
Help the needy!
帮助有需要的人。
Help the needy.
往锅里放点东西?
Put something in the pot?
哦，至少你有一个。
Oh, at least, you've got one.
帮助……谢谢您，先生。
Help... thank you, sir.
帮助有需要的人!
Help the needy!
谢谢你，女士。
Thank you, lady.
帮助有需要的人!
Help the needy!
帮助……谢谢你！
Help... thank you.
帮助有需要的人!
Help the needy!
谢谢你！
Thank you.
帮助有需要的人!
Help the needy!
谢谢你，女士。
Thank you, lady.
帮助有需要的人!
Help the needy!
圣诞快乐!
Merry Christmas!
Ho-ho-ho,哈哈!
Ho-ho-ho, ho-ho!
我……祝福您，善良的先生。
Me... blessings on you, kind sir.
圣诞快乐。
Merry Christmas.
Oh-ho-ho !
Oh-ho-ho!
Ho-ho-ho !
Ho-ho-ho!
基督快乐……圣诞快乐!
Merry Christ... merry Christmas!
圣诞快乐!
Merry Christmas!
空空的快乐……哈哈,哈哈!
Merry Chr... ho-ho, ho-ho!
圣诞快乐!
Merry Christmas!
快乐……嗯哼，圣诞快乐!
Merry... ahem, merry Christmas!
哈哈,哈哈!
Ho-ho, ho-ho!
圣诞快乐!
Merry Christmas!
《铃儿响叮当》!
Jingle bells!
圣诞快乐!
Happy yuletide!
快乐……圣诞老人送的小礼物?
Merry... little something from Santa?
圣诞快乐!
Merry Christmas!
哈……这不是从佛罗里达来的柠檬小子吗。
Ha... Well, if it isn't the Lemon Drop Kid back from Florida.
圣诞快乐!
Merry Christmas!
“拯救生命。”
"Save a Life."
谁的生活?
Who's life?
我的。
Mine.
来吧，孩子。
Come on, Kid.
哦，不，等一下。
Oh, no, wait a minute.
我什么都没做。
I haven't done anything.
我是无辜的。
I'm innocent.
我只是个小商人。
I'm just a small businessman.
我是做圣诞老人生意的。
I'm in the Santa Claus business.
来吧，圣诞老人。
Come along, Santa.
我打电话叫驯鹿来。
I'll phone for the reindeer.
哦，我打车去车站接你。
Oh, I'll take a cab and meet you at the station.
西德尼·米尔本。
Sidney Milburn.
西德尼·米尔本!
Sidney Milburn!
法官阁下，那是柠檬小子。
Your Honor, that's the Lemon Drop Kid.
柠檬小子在为慈善机构募捐却没有执照。
The Lemon Drop Kid was collecting money for charity Without a license.
慈善是什么?
What charity?
他自己的，法官阁下
His own, Your Honor.
你如何辩护?
How do you plead?
法官阁下，我想请求将这个案子推迟到1月1日当我的律师从华盛顿回来时。
Well, Your Honor, I'd like to ask For a postponement of this case until January 1 When my attorney returns from Washington.
华盛顿?
Washington?
是的，他在下面帮杜鲁门总统处理一张停车罚单。
Yeah, he's down there trying to fix a parking Ticket for President Truman.
米尔本，你对行乞的指控有何辩护?
Milburn, how do you plead to this charge of panhandling?
行乞呢?
Panhandling?
我拿着铃铛和水壶站在角落里，就像成百上千个普通的美国圣诞老人一样。
I was standing in the corner with my bell and kettle, Like hundreds of other everyday average American Santa Clauses.
你收集这笔钱是为了一己私利。
You were collecting this money for your own personal gain.
其他人都在为慈善事业工作。
Those other men are working for charity.
这是一个有组织的慈善机构，有市政执照。
It's an organized charity and has a city license.
嗯。
Eh.
哦，城市执照。
Oh, a city license.
米尔本先生，我要把这笔钱捐给一个有价值的慈善机构。
Mr. Milburn, I'm going to turn this money over To a worthwhile charity.
十天或五十美元。
Ten days or fifty dollars.
哦，但是我没有50美元。
Oh, but I haven't got fifty dollars.
我可抽不出十天的时间。
And I can't spare ten days.
我们会为您安排时间。
We'll arrange your schedule to spare it for you.
下一个例子。
Next case.
哦，但是，法官，拜托。
Oh, but, Judge, please.
法官阁下，我能打个电话吗?
Your Honor, could I make one phone call?
是的。
Yes.
这是异地恋，我…
It's long distance, I...
来吧。
Come on.
在我看来那个法官不诚实。
That judge didn't look honest to me.
18年来，他一直是律师协会的成员。
For 18 years, he's been a member of the bar.
这就是我的意思。
That's what I mean.
上班时喝酒。
Drinking on duty.
你好,孩子。
Hello, Kid.
内莉吗?
Nellie?
你在这里做什么?
What are you doing here?
问他。
Ask him.
他逮捕了我因为我试图把我的私人物品带出我的公寓。
He had me arrested for trying to get my personal belongings out Of my apartment.
但他甚至都不想让我给亨利拍照。
But he didn't even want me to take Henry's picture.
这是他唯一拍过的照片。
That's the only picture he ever had taken.
天啊，一点都没变。
Gee, hasn't changed a bit.
我们走吧。
Let's go.
你这个打女人的。
You woman beater.
来吧。
Come on.
叽阿。
Grrr.
来吧。
Come on.
来吧!
Come on!
哦，等等，等等。
Uh, oh, hold it, hold it.
举行什么?
Hold what?
持有这些。
Hold these.
法官说我可以请律师。
Judge told me I could call my lawyer.
你说你的律师在华盛顿。
You said your lawyer was in Washington.
是的，是邓肯，芒坎，施芒坎和布雷尼的公司。
Yeah, it's a firm of Duncan, Muncan, Schmuncan, and Brainey.
孩子，等我的律师跟你谈完，你就得半吊子了。
Boy, when my lawyer gets through with you, You'll be wearing your brass buttons at half mast.
喂?
Hello?
我…哦。
I... oh.
喂，布莱尼在吗?
Hello, is Brainey there?
是吗?
Yeah?
你好，Brainey。
Well, hello, Brainey.
你好,亲爱的。
Hiya, honey.
是个女律师。
It's a lady lawyer.
聪明宝贝，你以为我在哪里?
Brainey baby, where do you think I am?
别告诉我。
Don't tell me.
让我猜猜。
Let me guess.
当然是执照局。
The license bureau, of course.
你嫁给了自己。
You married yourself.
多么舒适。
How cozy.
现在,看看。
Now, look.
我是从执照局开始的，宝贝。
I started for the license bureau, baby.
但在下来的路上，我在我以前的宿舍停了下来给你拍了张照片。
But on the way down, I stopped off at my old rooming house To get your photograph.
我喜欢和你不在一起的时候看看它。
I like to look at it when I'm not with you.
房东不让我进去拿。
Well, the landlord wouldn't let me in to get it.
一件事接一件事。
So one thing led to another.
他戳了我一下。
He poked me.
我戳了他一下。
I poked him.
你觉得我现在在哪?
And where do you think I am?
在牢房里。
In the pokey.
狭小的吗?
The pokey?
呆在那里，保持你原来的样子，美丽。
Stay there, just the way you are, beautiful.
我想记住你微笑的样子。
I want to remember you smiling.
微笑?
Smiling?
看，谁在笑?
Look, who's smiling?
我…你能离开镇子几个小时吗，拜托了?
I'd... Look, would you leave town for a couple of hours, please?
听着，聪明宝贝，你得听我说。
Look, Brainey baby, you got to listen to me.
听你的?
Listen to you?
我的皮大衣听了你的话。
My fur coat listened to you.
我的十块钱听了你的话。
My ten bucks listened to you.
我听了你的话。
I listened to you.
我们都听够了你的话。
We're all fed up listening to you.
嗨，布雷尼，我们开始了!
Hey, Brainey, we're on!
再见，小子。
So long, Kid.
圣诞快乐!
Merry Christmas!
记住，如果我不联系你，无论如何，不要联系我。
And remember, if I don't get in touch with you, by all means, Don't get in touch with me.
不，Brainey, Brainey, Brainey宝贝。
No, Brainey, Brainey, Brainey baby.
Brainey，去…好吧，呃，我…拿着这个。
Brainey, go to... right, uh, I, wha... here hold this.
她不能这样对我。
She can't do this to me.
回来吧，圣诞老人。
Come back here, Santa.
你会……至少，我不赔不赚。
Would you... at least, I broke even.
然后你听到一声咆哮，你以为他们还想要更多，所以你开始疯狂地唱歌。
Then you hear such a roar, And you think they want more, so you start in singing like mad.
你可以看到我们的形状很好。
You can see that we're shaped well.
你看，我们披得很好。
You see that we're draped well.
但我们可以从那些目瞪口呆的家伙身上看出来。
But we can tell by the fellows that gape.
他们喜欢听我们唱红红的歌。
Well, they like to hear us sing in the pink.
哦，邓克先生，多漂亮的貂皮啊。
Oh, Mr. Dunker, what a beautiful mink.
当你听到我唱，啊-啊-啊，啊-啊-啊，你一定会从每一小节中得到快乐!
You must get pleasure from every measure when you hear me sing, Ah-ah-ah, ah-ah-ah!
我认为。
I think.
我的想法吗?
I think?
当我们发声时，你的反应令人惊讶。
Your reaction is surprising when we're doing our vocalizing.
是啊，你显然是来看我们唱歌的。
Yes, you obviously came just to see us sing.
好吧,女孩。
OK, girls.
6点回来。
Back at 6 o'clock.
-嗨。-嗨。
- Hi. - Hi.
一些早餐吗?
Some breakfast?
不用了，谢谢。
No, thank you.
查理，我不知道怎么…是的，是的，我知道。
Charlie, I don't know how... Yeah, yeah, I know.
我听说柠檬小子去酒壶了。
I heard about the Lemon Drop Kid going to the jug.
多少钱?
How much?
五十岁。
Fifty.
用我的工资。
Out of my salary.
嗯。
Hm.
你知道吗，为什么每次我追求一个女人，她最后都嫁给了那个鼓手?
You know, why is it every time I go for a dame, She winds up marrying the drummer?
大概在两个金发女郎之前，我在兰花和珍珠上花了很多钱，她勾搭上了一个服务员。
About two blondes ago, I shell a lot Of fortune in orchids and pearls, She hooks up with a waiter.
是啊，一个小胖子。
Huh, yeah, a little fat guy.
我才不要跟什么服务员搞在一起呢。
Well, I'm not getting hooked up with any waiter.
那小子骗了我几次，我不会让他得逞的。
The Kid pulled a couple of fast ones on me, And I'm not letting him get away with it.
他认为他在监狱里很安全。
He thinks he's safe in jail.
嗯。
Hm.
谢谢你,查理。
Thanks, Charlie.
我会还你钱的。
I'll pay you back in money.
是的。
Yeah.
怎么了，圣诞老人?
What's the matter, Santa Claus?
你的驯鹿闯红灯了?
Your reindeer gone through a red light?
圣诞老人今年不是个好孩子。
Santa Claus hasn't been a good boy this year.
他们在你包里发现了什么，圣诞老人?
What did they find in your bag, Santa?
盗窃工具吗?
Burglary tools?
乌合之众。
Riffraff.
有人来看你了，小子。
You got a visitor, Kid.
你的家庭医生。
Your family doctor.
嗯，外科医生山姆。
Well, Sam the Surgeon.
你提前来切圣诞菜了吗?
You come to do your Christmas chopping early?
不,圣诞老人。
No, Santa.
我是来提醒你慕斯·莫兰想要什么圣诞礼物的。
I came to remind you what Moose Moran wants for Christmas.
我记得。
I remember.
你知道吗，小子，躲在监狱里太蠢了。
You know, Kid, jail's a silly place to try to hide.
慕斯的朋友进的比出的多。
Moose has more friends in than out.
山姆，你可以把刀放在樟脑丸里。
Sam, you can put your knife in mothballs.
我有个好主意。
I got an idea that can't miss.
我知道我能弄到一万美元。
I know I can come up with the ten grand.
没关系，因为一些聪明的男孩开始逗慕斯笑了，慕斯不喜欢这样。
That's fine because some of the smart boys Are starting to get Moose to laugh, and Moose don't like it.
我们要做的就是从现在开始借用穆斯的赌场直到圣诞节。
All we have to do is borrow Moose's casino from now Till Christmas.
慕斯不能打开它进行高级赌博。
Moose can't open it for high-class gambling.
你连宾果游戏厅都打不开。
You can't even open it for a bingo parlor.
等等，你在和一个天才说话。
Wait, you're talking to a genius.
你认识Nellie Thursday吗?
You know Nellie Thursday?
她在这里。
She's in here.
她没有地方住。
She's got no place to live.
她想进养老院，但他们不收她，因为她丈夫有前科。
She tried to get into an old folks' home, But they wouldn't take her on account Of her husband's an ex-con.
这是我的想法。
Now, here's the idea.
我借了穆斯的赌场。
I borrow Moose's casino.
我假装这是一家老人院。
I pretend it's an old folks' home.
我把内莉和一堆旧娃娃放在一起。
I stick Nellie in there with a bunch of old dolls.
有他们在里面……这部分有点难。
With them in it... now, this part is kind of tough.
但我想，如果我能做到，我可以说服市政府给我一张为慈善募捐的执照。
But I figure, uh, if I can work it, I can talk the city into giving me A license to collect for charity.
我还想，我可以把百老汇所有的杯子都拿来帮我收集。
I further figure, I can get every mug on Broadway To help me do the collecting.
他们都喜欢内莉。
They all love Nellie.
她真是个漂亮的老娃娃。
She's such a grand old doll.
你想在慕斯的赌场里卖掉一群旧娃娃吗?
You trying to unload a mob of old dolls in Moose's casino?
嘘。
Shh.
只到平安夜。
It's only until Christmas Eve.
到那时，我就能筹到足够的钱还清穆斯。
By then, I'll have collected enough to pay off Moose.
这是我听过的最合法的欺骗。
This is the most legal double cross I've ever heard.
但是圣诞夜过后这些旧娃娃怎么办呢?
But what happens to the old dolls after Christmas Eve?
如果募捐的钱突然丢了而那些旧娃娃也没钱待在赌场了，我能控制得了吗?
Well, can I help it if suddenly the collection money Just happens to get lost and the old dolls Can't afford to stay in the casino?
慕斯会得到他的钱。
Moose will have his dough.
这样我就不会有麻烦了。
And I'll be in the clear, you see.
你要在圣诞节的时候把那些漂亮的小女人都扔到大街上吗?
You're going to dump all those nice little ladies out On the street at Christmastime?
我不会对自己的母亲这么做。
I wouldn't do that to my own mother.
城里任何一家庄家都会给你3比1。
Any bookmaker in town will give you 3-1.
这到底算不算交易?
Is it a deal or not?
听起来很疯狂。
Sounds crazy.
但那不是我的部门。
But that ain't my department.
如果你不给我钱，我就开始手术。
I only to start operating if you don't pay off.
你在哪里实习过?
Where did you intern at?
财务公司?
The finance company?
嘿，山姆，五十美元的罚款有点小问题。
And hey, Sam, there's a little matter of the fifty-dollar fine.
你先垫付，我就欠慕斯一万五。
You advance it, and I owe Moose a round figure of ten thousand and fifty.
不，谢谢，小子。
No, thanks, Kid.
我喜欢你被冷冻起来。
I like having you in the deep freeze.
我们可以在假期前让你暖和起来。
We can thaw you out in time for the holiday season.
再过15天圣诞快乐。
Merry Christmas in just 15 days.
圣诞快乐。
Merry Christmas.
15天。
15 days.
我得离开这里。
I got to get out of here.
我得离开这里!
I got to get out of here!
请放我出去!
Please let me out of here!
嘿!
Hey!
我早就该说"请"了。
I should have said "please" a long time ago.
有一位女士在办公室等你。
There's a lady waiting for you in the office.
她付了你的罚款。
She paid your fine.
再见,圣诞老人!
Goodbye, Santa!
犯!
Delinquents!
这是您的收据。
Here's your receipt.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
Brainey !
Brainey!
我就知道你会来。
I knew you'd come.
无法抗拒，是吗?
Couldn't fight it, eh?
我不知道我会对他们做什么。
I don't know what I'd do to them.
我猜，你在想我的衣服。
Well, I guess, you're wondering about the outfit.
哦，不，运动。
Oh, no, sport.
你总是穿着华丽。
You always were a flashy dresser.
你不知道重获自由是什么感觉。
You don't know how it feels to be free again.
你大概有五分钟的空闲时间。
Well, you're going to be free about five minutes.
我们要去市中心领结婚证。
We're heading downtown for a marriage license.
在一起。
Together.
Brainey，你让我成为世界上最幸福的男人!
Brainey, you're making me the happiest man in the world!
而且再也不会有每周为了区区几块钱跳舞的机会了……当你是我妻子的时候。
And there'd be no more dancing for a few measly dollars A week anymore... not when you're my wife.
我们会让牛津查理给你加薪的。
We'll make Oxford Charlie give you a raise.
哦，我不想工作……想想看，再过几周，我们就是柠檬小子夫妇了。
Oh, I don't want to work... Just think, in a few short weeks, We'll be Mr. And Mrs. Lemon Drop Kid.
短短几周?
A few short weeks?
这次的摊位是什么?
What's the stall this time?
好吧，来吧。
Well, come on.
你会为我感到骄傲的。
You'll be proud of me.
哦。
Oops.
嗨，你好，小子。
Hic, hello, Kid.
又在看电视了?
Been watching television again, huh?
警官，罪名是什么?
What's the charge, Officer?
我跟你说话的时候你能别排练了吗?
Hey, will you stop rehearsing when I'm trying to talk to you?
还记得那次轮到你输的时候你赢了吗?
Remember the time you win when it was your turn to lose?
谁把你藏了三个星期?
Who hide you off for three weeks?
内莉。
Nellie did.
但是，小子，你的个人角度是什么?
But, Kid, what's your personal angle?
闭上嘴，瑞典佬。
Button your lips, Swede.
内莉就像你的母亲。
Nellie is like a mother to you.
叽阿。
Grrr.
柠檬娃娃?
Lemon Drop Kid?
我只是不相信你不关心柠檬滴小孩。
I just don't believe you're not looking out For the Lemon Drop Kid.
但你必须相信。
But you got to believe it.
像Nellie Thursday这样的老太太肯定有好几百个。
There must be hundreds of old ladies like Nellie Thursday.
它们遍布百老汇大街。
They're all around Broadway.
老娃娃们进不了家，因为他们可能在过去卷了一卷，捣碎了一点自制啤酒。
Old dolls who can't get into homes because maybe they Rolled a lusher, pound a little homemade beer in the old days.
甚至是你自己的母亲。
Maybe even your own mother.
他们从来没有责怪过妈妈。
They never hung no rap on Mom.
同花顺托尼，去年你穷困潦倒的时候，谁把你押在了一副有标记的新牌上?
Straight Flush Tony, when you were down and out last year, Who staked you to a new deck of marked cards?
内莉!
Nellie!
好的!
OK!
所以大家都回家好好睡一觉吧。
So everybody go home and get a good night's sleep.
明天中午我们都要起床。
We're all getting up at noon tomorrow.
她来了。
There she is.
记住，一个字也别说。
Remember, not a word.
这是一个惊喜派对。
This is a surprise party.
你好,内莉。
Hello, Nellie.
孩子!
Kid!
哦，阴郁而诚实的哈利。
Oh, Gloomy and Honest Harry.
嘿，内莉。
Hey there, Nellie.
内尔，出来的感觉怎么样?
Ha, Nell, how does it feel to be out?
冷。
Cold.
哦,我的。
Oh, my.
我们有辆好车在等你。
We got a hot car waiting for you.
你们什么时候开始喜欢偷这个了?
Since when have you boys gone in for swiping this?
我们以为你会喜欢兜风的。
Oh, we thought you'd enjoy a little ride.
谢谢，但我要走路。
Thanks, but I'm walking.
在转角处有个小公寓。
There's a two-bit boarding house just around the corner.
好的，我们开车送你去。
Good, we'll drive you there.
你疯了，小子。
Oh, you're crazy, Kid.
等等，谁会开豪华轿车去廉价公寓?
Wait, who pulls up to a cheap boarding house in a limousine?
只有和朋友在一起的旧娃娃。
Only old dolls with friends.
进去。
Get in.
小子，这不是穆斯·莫兰以前的赌场吗?
Why, Kid, isn't this Moose Moran's old gambling casino?
穆斯·莫兰的老什么?
Moose Moran's old what?
“奈莉星期四回家给老娃娃。”
"Nellie Thursday Home for Old Dolls."
这是什么意思，小子?
What does this mean, Kid?
只是长岛的一间小公寓，内莉。
It's just a two-bit boarding house in Long Island, Nellie.
整块地都是后院，冷热相间的矮牵牛花，四面朝南，灰泥浴缸。
Whole field for a backyard, hot and cold running petunias, Southern exposure on all sides, stucco bathtubs.
对了，我差点忘了，有个房间给亨利，里面有个很大的保险箱供他练习。
Oh yeah, I almost forgot, there's A room for Henry with a nice big safe for him to practice on.
嘿,小子。
Hey, Kid.
我和Goomba在公园里发现了这个…解锁。
Me and Goomba found this in the park... unlocked.
我们觉得这样对内莉比较好。
We thought it'd be nice for Nellie.
干得好，Solly。
Oh, good work, Solly.
把它放在草坪上。
Put it out on the lawn.
她在厕所…雕像旁边看起来不错。
She's loo... looking good by the statue.
雕像?
Statue?
听着，我们没有…
Look, we don't have...
将军在中央公园已经坐得够久了。
The general has been sitting in Central Park long enough.
我们觉得他需要换个环境。
We figure he needs a change of scenery.
你把那个将军放回马背上。
You take that general and put him back on his horse.
随你怎么说，小子。
Anything you say, Kid.
我们也觉得将军没了马一定很寂寞。
We, too, figured that general was lonesome without his horse.
他们可能还带了鸽子。
They probably brought the pigeons, too.
嘿，同花顺，帮帮他们?
Hey, Straight Flush, help them, huh?
你还以为我们带你来这里是为了拿免费报纸吗?
You still think we carried you out here To get free newspapers?
你做的…这是一家老人院，不是吗?
You did... it is an old folks' home, isn't it?
当然是。
Sure, it is.
最好的。
The best.
我们会让阳光之家的捕鼠器对我们的溢流感到满意。
We'll make that Sunshine Home rat Trap be satisfied with our overflow.
你做这一切都是为了我?
And you did all this for me?
原来你是百老汇最受欢迎的洋娃娃。
Turns out you're the most popular doll on Broadway.
街上每个骗子都在为你卖命。
Every chiseler on the street is knocking himself out for you.
孩子，我听说过这个地方的时候它还很开放。
Kid, I hear about this place when it was wide open.
但我从不进去。
But I'm never inside.
这是专门给肿胀用的。
It's strictly for swells.
不了。
Not anymore.
百老汇欢迎任何坏掉的旧娃娃。
Any broken down old doll on Broadway is welcome.
惊喜!
Surprise!
内莉，以防你需要朋友来玩金拉米或者垒球，我们买了很多旧娃娃。
Nellie, in case you're needing some friends To play gin rummy or maybe a game of softball, We loaded up on old dolls.
欢迎回家，内莉。
Welcome home, Nellie.
Brainey。
Brainey.
你还记得鲍姆加滕太太吗?
You remember Mrs. Baumgarten?
唱着Solly的岳母。
Singing Solly's mother-in-law.
唱歌的索利捐了她。
Singing Solly donated her.
是啊，她在这里会更开心。
Yeah, she'd be much happier here.
母亲住在他们的房子里，这对已婚夫妇总是很紧张。
It's always a strain on the married couple with the mother Living in their house.
但那是我的房子。
But it was my house.
嘿,小子。
Hey, Kid.
出来一下。
Come out here a minute.
哦，马上，阴郁。
Oh, right away, Gloomy.
带内莉见见姐妹会的其他成员，好吗?
See that Nellie meets the rest of the sorority, will you?
孩子，哦，太棒了。
Kid, oh, it's oh so wonderful.
我没什么好说的。
There's nothing I can say.
只是不知道该怎么说。
Just haven't got the words.
好。
Good.
让我们保持这种状态。
Let's keep it that way.
不要说废话。
Say no yak-yak.
臭鼻子发现了这个漂亮的老太太住在桥下的小屋里。
Pickle-nose found this nice little old lady Living in a shack under the bridge.
你好啊，可爱的老太太。
Well, hello, nice little old lady.
欢迎来到耐莉星期四之家。
Welcome to the Nellie Thursday Home.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
这是什么?
What's this?
我的金丝雀。
My canary.
我拥有她九年了。
I've had her nine years.
那对一只鸟来说太老了。
Well, that's old for a bird.
她也可以留下。
She can stay, too.
哦，你真贴心。
Oh, you're a sweet.
你也很可爱，臭鼻子。
You're sweet, too, Pickle-nose.
把椅子拿过来。
Bring the chair.
快点，快点。
Hurry up, hurry up.
把她拉下来。
Bring her down.
把它拿出来。
Bring it out.
你拿的是什么，霍根?
What do you got there, Hogan?
我们给他们的咖啡加了奶油。
We got cream for their coffee.
嘘。
Shh.
你想把邻居的牛都吵醒吗?
You want to wake up all the neighbors' cows?
嘘。
Shh.
我们需要一头牛，是吧?
We need a cow, huh?
你以为你是谁?
Who do you think you are?
Hopalong卡西迪吗?
Hopalong Cassidy?
在赌桌上放两块垫子。
Put two of those mats on the crap tables.
我们得把这些娃娃叠起来。
We'll have to double up these dolls.
luck -a-luck和轮盘赌都很小，我们得挤两个。
Chuck-a-luck and roulette are small, We'd have to squeeze two on.
快点，斯利姆。
Snap it up, Slim.
你看起来像个女服务员。
You look like a chambermaid.
是海军上将酒店捐赠的吗?
Did the Admiral Hotel donate this linen?
是的，但我们还没告诉他们。
Yeah, but we haven't told them yet.
好吧,男人。
OK, men.
那些不是床垫。
Those aren't mattresses.
当然不是。
Of course not.
这是斯蒂尔曼健身房的。
They're from Stillmann's gym.
它们是摔跤垫。
They're wrestling mats.
你不会指望这些老女人睡在空荡荡的破桌子上吧?
You don't expect these old gals to sleep on bare crap tables?
孩子，你不是很聪明，但你的心是对的。
Kid, you're not very bright, but your heart's In the right place.
别喋喋不休了，整理床铺。
Cut out the chatter and make the beds.
这些老女人随时会从化妆室里冲出来。
These old gals will be fussing out Of the powder room any minute.
我很乐意去睡觉。
I'll be glad to go to bed.
我也能站着睡一会儿。
I can stand for a little sleep, too.
嗯，我也困了。
Well, I'm sleepy, too.
这些袖子比我的胳膊长。
These sleeves are longer than my arms.
在里面不是很好吗?
Isn't it nice to be in there?
你看起来真棒!
Ho, you look wonderful!
马克西·罗森布鲁姆当冠军的时候可没那么帅。
Maxie Rosenbloom didn't look that good when he was champ.
多么可爱的床。
Such lovely beds.
所以现代的。
So modernistic.
是啊，我们只是用了几天垃圾桌直到我们在收集上领先。
Yeah, we're just using the crap tables for a few days Till we get ahead in the collections.
然后我们把床铺好。
Then we're putting in beds.
床上吗?
Beds?
谁在乎呢?
Well, who cares?
亨利可以在平安夜来这里。
Henry can come here Christmas Eve.
我们会有朋友……当然，现在大家都去睡觉吧。
And we'll have friends... Sure, now hit the sack, everybody.
Beddy-byes。
Beddy-byes.
谁在玩这个游戏?
Who's playing the field?
在跳。
Jump in.
夯实垫子。
Tamp the mat.
哦，她起来了，看。
Oop, she's up, see.
你是甜的。
You're sweet.
Tsup。
Tsup.
你要是从桌子上滚下去，就没戏了。
You roll off the table, it's no dice.
现在，去睡觉吧。
Now, go to sleep.
别担心亨利。
And don't worry about Henry.
等他来了，我们就让他当私家侦探。
When he gets here, we'll make him house detective.
孩子?
Kid?
是的吗?
Yup?
有件事困扰着我。
There's something bothering me.
是吗?
Yeah?
什么?
What?
一切都进展得太快了，我刚开始想。
Well, everything's been moving so fast, I just started thinking.
孩子，你确定穆斯·莫兰把这里交给我们了吗?
Kid, are you sure that Moose Moran turned this place over To us?
哦，他当然有。
Oh, ho-ho, sure he did.
现在，你让我来操心，好吗?
Now, you let me do all the worrying, will you?
我只是觉得慕斯从来都不太慷慨。
Well, it's just that Moose never Struck me as being generous.
你不能告诉别人，内莉。
You can't tell about people, Nellie.
有些坏人内心是善良的。
Some of the bad ones are good inside.
有些善良的人内心是邪恶的。
And some of the good ones are bad inside.
好吧，时间不早了。
OK, it's getting late.
现在是摇篮曲时间。
It's lullaby time.
现在，让我们每个人都来大打出手，好吗?
Now, let's everybody snore it up real big, huh?
孩子?
Kid?
是吗?
Yeah?
你能帮我盖好被子吗?
Would you tuck me in, too?
是啊。
LEMON DROP KID Yeah.
把鸟笼罩上，好吗，孩子?
Put the shade over the birdcage, wouldn't you, Kid?
好的。
OK.
这就像经营一个陈旧的托儿所。
It's like running a stale nursery.
大家都去睡觉吧。
Everybody go to sleep.
一分钟内还没睡着的娃娃明天就别去玩老虎机了。
Any doll who isn't asleep in one minute Don't get any slugs tomorrow to play the slot machines.
孩子，你能把灯再开一会儿吗?
Kid, could you leave the lights on maybe a little longer?
哦,当然。
Oh, sure.
放松。
Relax.
让穆斯·莫兰的赌场大开特开。
Make like Moose Moran's casino is wide open.
你连续扔了11个7。
You're throwing 11 sevens in a row.
筹码堆成一堆。
The chips are building up in stacks.
我和布雷尼是来给你一堆梦的。
Me and Brainey are here to deal you out a whole deck of dreams.
我们将向你展示如何拥有一颗卫星。
We'll show you how to own a moon.
以及如何像玩具气球一样弹跳世界。
And how to bounce the world just like a toy balloon.
我们会告诉你怎么走自己的路。
We'll show you how to have your way.
请用银托盘来许愿。
And help yourself to wishes on a silver tray.
你想飞往巴厘岛或选择另一个你想买的岛屿。
You want to fly to Bali Hai or pick Another island you would like to buy.
曼哈顿怎么样?
How about Manhattan?
当你熟睡的时候，你可以便宜地旅行，因为做梦不需要花一分钱。
You can travel cheap when you're fast asleep 'Cause it doesn't cost a dime to dream.
我们会在墙上贴满美钞用皱巴巴的美钞擦窗台。
We'll line our walls with dollar bills And use the wrinkled ones to wipe out windowsills.
把我们的旧香槟倒进厨房的下水道。
Pour our old champagne down the kitchen drain.
不，梦想不需要花费一分钱。
No, it doesn't cost a dime to dream.
我们会在总统's…恩,哒……家庭住宅。
We will call at the president's... tada, dah... Family residence.
还清国家债务。
Pay off the national debt.
你是个梦想家吗?
Are you a dreamer?
如果我们发现总统有点犹豫，我们就说我们还有很多剩余。
And if we find the president slightly hesitant, We'll say we have a lot left yet.
一个漂亮的家。
A fancy home.
为什么，这很简单。
Why, that's a snap.
从一个房间到另一个房间，我们得有个垫子。
To get from room to room, we'll have to have a mat.
只要闭上眼睛，就能看到这份奖赏。
Just to see this prize, only close your eyes.
梦想不需要花费一分钱。
It doesn't cost a dime to dream.
我们玩轮盘赌。
We play roulette.
我们下注。
We place our bets.
tw !
Twing!
我们输了一百万，还切薄饼。
We lose a million bucks and cut up Crepes Suzettes.
打电话给美国造币厂。
Call the US Mint.
他们会打印我们需要的东西。
What we need, they'll print.
梦想不需要花费一分钱。
It doesn't cost a dime to dream.
我们会有一个女仆，她有一个女仆女仆有一个女仆给两个女仆倒柠檬水。
We'll have a maid who has a maid who Has a maid to serve the two maids lemonade.
我们会像水一样花掉我们的面团。
We will spend our dough just like H2O.
在西班牙租一个小镇来娱乐。
Rent a town in Spain just to entertain.
掷骰子，看筹码滚滚而来，如果你注意我们的计划。
Give the dice a spin, watch the chips roll in, If you pay attention to our scheme.
所以你会不会去睡觉，数几只纯种的羊，因为这不用花一分钱…嘘……梦想。
So won't you go to sleep, count some pedigreed sheep 'Cause it doesn't cost a dime... shh... to dream.
熄灯。
Lights out.
哦。
Oops.
一定是按了起跑门。
Must have pressed the starting gate.
嘿，内莉，矮桥!
Hey, Nellie, low bridge!
你觉得怎么样?
How do you like that?
骰子桌被扔进壁炉里了。
The dice table went in the fireplace.
他们去了哪里?
Where did they go?
我们得把慕斯的线路换了。
Hey, we'll have to change Moose's wiring.
我们预计不会有任何突袭。
We don't expect any raids.
嘿,小子!
Hey, Kid!
这是什么?
What is this?
好吧，关掉它。
Well, turn it off.
快!
Quick!
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
这是错误的。
That's the wrong one.
你想要我怎么样?
What do you want from me?
我不是电工。
I'm no electrician.
找奥逊·威尔斯。
Get Orson Welles.
嘿!
Hey!
现在，你满意了吗?
Now, are you satisfied?
我们明天开始收集，你把旧娃娃藏起来。
We start collecting tomorrow, and you hide the old dolls.
带上你的盗窃工具。
Get your burglary tools.
我们得把它们挖出来。
We'll have to dig them out.
啧啧。
Tsk.
挖得好，伙计们。
Good digging, men.
我为你感到骄傲。
I'm proud of you.
哦，谢谢你，先生。
Oh, thank you, sir.
哦，他很可爱。
Oh, he's darling.
来吧。
Come on.
我们离开这里吧。
Let's get out of here.
是的。
Yeah.
快乐男孩。
The Happiness Boys.
孩子。
Kid.
是的。
Yeah.
你是不是忘了什么东西?
Haven't you forgotten something?
你是说，我们没把他们都救出来?
You mean, we didn't get them all out?
不。
No.
那是……你照顾那些旧娃娃。
That was... You took care of the old dolls.
你知道，这就是小娃娃变成老娃娃的方式。
You know, this is the way young dolls become old dolls.
天啊，我要订一把摇椅。
My, I'll order a rocking chair.
订个双座的，好吗?
Make it a two-seater, huh?
我讨厌接吻时按喇叭。
I hate honking during smooching.
来吧，孩子。
Come on, Kid.
我累了。
I'm tired.
我们上路吧。
Let's hit the road.
你听到了。
You heard him.
路上喝一杯?
One for the road?
好的，但是小心驾驶。
OK, but drive carefully.
男人在工作。
Men at work.
你永远也冻不起来的。
You'll never freeze that stuff.
先生们，和我想象的一样。
Gentlemen, just as I pictured you.
嘿，把这个捡起来，好吗?
Hey, pick this up a little, will you?
你看起来像个扒手。
You look like a shoplifter.
圣诞老人不抽烟。
Saint Nick don't smoke.
我以为我是圣诞老人?
I thought I was supposed to be Santa Claus?
圣诞老人，圣诞老人，圣诞老人。
Santa Claus, Kris Kringle, Saint Nick.
都是同一个人。
It's all the same guy.
哦，我明白了。
Oh, I get it.
他也没说出真名。
He don't give his right name either.
教授，你好吗?
How are you doing, Professor?
算出来。
Work it out.
小子，这些东西里没有口袋。
Hey, Kid, there are no pockets in these things.
是的，我们是这么安排的。
Yeah, we arranged it that way.
嘿，同花顺，让我们听你敲钟。
Hey, Straight Flush, let's hear you ring the bell.
不，不，不。
No, no, no.
又不是说你想让事情变得更糟。
Not like you're trying to make it fall the hard way.
铃儿响叮当。
Jingle bells.
哦，真贴心。
Oh, now, that's sweet.
你要做大生意了。
You're going to do a big business.
谢谢。
Thanks.
嗯，外面街上很冷。
Well, it's cold out there in the street.
圣诞老人不喝酒。
Santa Claus don't drink.
哦,不是吗?
Oh, no?
他怎么总是从烟囱里掉下来?
Well, how come he's always falling down chimneys?
哦，太好了。
Oh, that's great.
他们做了什么?
What did they do?
从里面切?
Cut that from the inside?
别吓到太多人，好吗?
Now, don't scare too many people, huh?
让我们听听你怎么说。
Let's hear it from you.
祝你圣诞快乐。
A merry krismees.
在你自己的社区工作。
Just work your own neighborhood.
很好,男人。
Great, men.
了不起的一群人。
Splendid group of men.
别一副跟驯鹿打交道的样子。
Now, don't look like you're handling hot reindeer.
记住，这是合法的生意。
Remember, this is a legitimate business.
我们有执照可以收钱。
We got a license to collect.
现在，走出去，全身心地投入到工作中去，就像你做了一笔见不得光的交易。
Now, just get out there and put your heart Into you work, just like you would if it was a shady deal.
嘿,小子。
Hey, Kid.
那其他的圣诞老人呢?
What about them other Santas?
是啊，街上到处都是又老又胖的家伙。
Yeah, the streets are lousy with jolly old, fat guys.
我们要把子弹对准他们。
We'll put the slug on them.
是的。
Yeah.
哦，现在，等一下。
Oh, now, wait a minute.
等一下。
Wait a minute.
你不能随便拿其他圣诞老人开涮，尤其是在这个季节。
You can't go around putting the slug in other Santa Clauses, Especially at this time of the year when they're in season.
现在，打开罐子，关上陷阱。
Now, keep your pots open and your traps shut.
我们得弄到一万块钱。
We got to get ten grand.
这是生死攸关的事
It's a matter of life and death.
谁要是没拿到定额就把旧娃娃扔到雪地里，就我个人而言，这是在耍我。
Anybody who doesn't collect their quota Is throwing an old doll out into the snow, and personally, Doing me a very dirty trick.
注意,男人。
Attention, men.
调整靴子，腹部，胡须。
Adjust boots, bellies, beards.
现在，出去把你的罐子装上。
Now, go out and load your pots.
前进。
Forward march.
叮叮当，叮叮当。
Jingle bells, jingle bells.
一路叮当响。
Jingle all the way.
哦，坐在单马雪橇上多有趣啊。
Oh, what fun it is to ride in a one-horse open sleigh.
哦，叮叮当，叮叮当。
Oh, jingle bells, jingle bells.
一路叮当响……帮帮可怜的内莉吧，伙计们。
Jingle all the way... Help poor Nellie, folks.
把它放进锅里。
Chunk it in the pot.
是善良的。
Be kind.
谢谢，亲爱的。
Oh, thanks, honey.
谢谢。
Thanks.
圣诞老人，平安夜你会来我家吗?
Santa, are you coming to my house Christmas Eve?
当然，当然，小母马。
Oh, sure, sure, little filly.
圣诞老人将在那里平安夜。
Santy will be there Christmas Eve.
你会带娃娃来吗?
Are you going to bring a doll?
不，我的娃娃在平安夜工作。
No, my doll's working Christmas Eve.
哦，你是说娃娃?
Oh, you mean a doll?
是的。
Yeah.
确定。
Sure.
听起来像个骗子。
Sounded like a phony.
给老太太们一些东西。
Give something for the old ladies.
为了善良的老太太，什么都可以。
Anything for the nice, old ladies.
给老太太们一些东西。
Give something for the old ladies.
一切都是为了美好…
Anything for the nice...
非常感谢，伙计们。
Thanks a lot, fellas.
圣诞快乐。
Merry Christmas.
哦，你这个耐莉·星期四回家!
Oh, you Nellie Thursday Home!
他是热的!
He's hot!
天啊，他太性感了!
Oh, man, is he hot!
银铃，银铃。
Silver bells, silver bells.
我们把娃娃放进猫里吧。
Let's put some doll in the kitty.
把它塞进去。
Chunk it in.
不然圣诞老人会给你米奇的。
Or Santy will give you a mickey.
银铃，银铃……嗨，小子。
Silver bells, silver be... oh, hi, Kid.
你好,Brainey。
Hello, Brainey.
你好,悲观。
Hello, Gloomy.
等一下。
Wait a minute.
你不用搜我身。
You don't have to frisk me.
我不会瞒着你的。
I ain't holding out on you.
那些顾客只是不喜欢金币，仅此而已。
Them shoppers just ain't breaking Loose with the guineas, that's all.
难怪他们不把它分块…你对他们咆哮的样子。
Well, no wonder they ain't chunking it In... the way you're growling at them.
嗯，怎么了?
Well, what's the matter?
是你叫我们唱歌的，对吧?
You told us to sing, didn't you?
唱歌,是的。
Sing, yeah.
但在圣诞节期间提到钱是庸俗的。
But to mention money at Christmastime is vulgar.
你得努力打动他们的情绪。
You've got to work on their sentiments.
要微妙、细腻。
Be subtle, delicate.
银铃，银铃。
Silver bells, silver bells.
现在是城里的圣诞节。
It's Christmastime in the city.
铃声，听到他们的铃声。
Ring-a-ling, hear them ring.
很快就到圣诞节了。
Soon it will be Christmas Day.
城市的人行道，繁忙的人行道，穿着节日的风格。
City sidewalks, busy sidewalks, dressed in holiday style.
空气中弥漫着圣诞节的气氛。
In the air, there's a feeling of Christmas.
孩子们在笑，人们在路过，相逢一个接一个的微笑。
Children laughing, people passing, Meeting smile after smile.
在每个街角你都能听到。
And on every street corner you'll hear.
银色的铃铛。
Silver bells.
我喜欢这套圣诞老人装。
I love this Santa suit.
银色的铃铛。
Silver bells.
装满战利品就行了。
Just fill it up with loot.
现在是城里的圣诞节。
It's Christmastime in the city.
Ring-a-ling。
Ring-a-ling.
哦，玲，哦，玲，哦，玲。
Oh, ling, oh, ling, oh, ling.
听他们的铃声。
Hear them ring.
为了我和我的玛丽。
For me and my Marie.
很快就到圣诞节了。
Soon it will be Christmas Day.
圣诞节让你情绪激动。
Christmas makes you feel emotional.
它可能带来党派或虔诚的思想。
It may bring parties or thoughts devotional.
无论发生什么或可能发生什么，这就是圣诞节对我的意义。
Whatever happens or what may be, Here is what Christmastime means to me.
一串串的路灯。
Strings of streetlights.
就连红绿灯都闪烁着明亮的红色和绿色，因为购物者带着他们的宝贝冲回家。
Even stoplights blink a bright red and green As the shoppers rush home with their treasures.
听到雪的嘎吱声，看到孩子们。
Hear the snow crunch, see the kids bunch.
圣诞老人的大场面。
This Santa's big scene.
在这喧嚣之中，你会听到。
And above all this bustle, you'll hear.
银色的铃铛。
Silver bells.
Du lieber das ist gut。
Du lieber das ist gut.
银色的铃铛。
Silver bells.
但你很可爱。
but you're cute.
城里的圣诞节到了。
It's Christmas time in the city.
嗯，城市执照。
Uh-uh, city license.
摇铃。
Ring a ling.
听他们的铃声。
Hear them ring.
银色的铃铛。
Silver bells.
节日花束。
A holiday bouquet.
我希望这是一辆雪橇。
I wish this was a sleigh.
找块骨头舔舔。
To get a bone to lick.
我想我看到了圣诞老人。
I think I see St. Nick.
圣诞节很快就要到了，圣诞节很快就要到了，圣诞节很快就要到了。
Soon it will be Christmas, Soon it will be Christmas, soon it will be Christmas Day.
银铃，银铃。
Silver bells, silver bells.
很快就到圣诞节了。
Soon it will be Christmas Day.
一，二，三。
One, two, three.
一、二、三……再见，布雷尼。
And one, two, three... Oh, goodbye, Brainey.
再见,Brainey。
Bye-bye, Brainey.
再见。
Bye-bye.
这么说你是在妨碍演出?
So you're ankling the show, huh?
直到圣诞节。
Just until Christmas.
那小子任命我为首席医生照顾奈莉·星期四之家。
The Kid has appointed me head chief doctor To watch over the Nellie Thursday Home.
那家伙到底有什么能耐让所有人都吓得跳起来?
What has that guy got that makes Everybody jump through a hoop?
骗局越疯狂，跳得越高。
The crazier the schemes, the higher they jump.
很多爱Nellie的人都不觉得这很疯狂。
A lot of people who love Nellie don't think it's so crazy.
像你这样聪明的女孩，会放弃工作。
Smart girl, like you, gives up a job.
街上每一个赌钱的人都在为你的老疯子捐钱。
Every penny ante character on the street Blows his top hustling donations for your old wacky.
也许古怪。
Maybe wacky.
但不是小赌注。
But not penny ante.
这是个大生意。
This is big business.
哈哈。
Ho-ho.
为什么，你知道在四天内，我们筹集了将近2000美元吗?
Why, do you know that in four days, we raised almost $2,000?
好吧。
All right.
所以你收集…那些穿宽松裤子的圣诞老人筹了两千?
So you collect... those baggy-pants Santas Raised two grand?
嗯嗯。
Mm-hm.
你看那小子在这里。
You see the Kid's got it here.
来，让我来。
Here, let me.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
你知道吗，Brainey，当你回来的时候，你的工作就会等着你，这证明我在这里没有。
You know, Brainey, your job will be waiting for you when You come back, which proves that I haven't got it here.
嘘，嘘，嘘。
Shh, shh, shh.
头皮屑,嗯?
Dandruff, huh?
准备好，你们这些野牛小弟，有印第安人来了。
Stand by, you Buffalo nickels, there's some Indians coming.
合众为一。
E pluribus unum.
嘘!
Shh!
安静,令人陶醉。
Quiet, Heady.
安静。
Quiet.
给你的菠菜来点苦头。
Giving you your spinach the hard way.
有趣的鼻子。
Funny nose.
银铃，银铃。
Silver bells, silver bells.
，战利品很不错。
, the loot is good.
呃，是你。
Uh, it's you.
我还以为是小偷呢。
I thought it was a prowler.
小偷吗?
A prowler?
有趣的事情。
Funny thing.
我在给我爱的女孩唱小夜曲，她却认为我是个小偷。
Here I am serenading the girl I love, And she thinks I'm a prowler.
嗯，我听到了一些声音。
Well, I heard some noise.
但我不知道它在唱歌。
But I didn't know it was singing.
我还没唱到副歌呢。
Uh, I didn't get to the chorus yet.
我只是在这里观察天空，想着你。
I was just out here casing the sky, thinking of you.
你知道吗，天上的每一颗星星都让我想起你眼中的光芒。
You know, every star up there reminds me Of the light in your eyes.
一闪一闪，小…哦。
Twinkle, twinkle, little... uh-oh.
闪烁,闪烁……那是小孩子的东西。
Twinkle, twinkle... That's kid stuff.
亲爱的，你的尖牙露出来了。
Honey, your fangs are showing.
如果你得意忘形了，不要克制自己，好吗?
If you get carried away, don't hold yourself back, ha?
孩子。
Kid.
亲爱的，永远不要失去我。
Honey, don't ever lose me.
那会毁了你的。
It would ruin you.
我们必须马上对柠檬滴小子施压。
We must lean in on the Lemon Drop Kid right away.
嘿，你不会是想让我们穿上猴子装然后摇起铃铛吧?
Hey, you ain't figuring on us wearing the monkey suits And ringing them little bells?
听着，如果那小子能在四天内筹到两千，我们能筹到更多。
Look, if the Kid can raise two grand in four days, We can raise lots more than that.
当然,老板。
Sure, boss.
孩子们在穆斯·莫兰的赌场里买了一堆旧娃娃。
The kids got a herd of old dolls in Moose Moran's casino.
他就是这样拿到驾照的。
This is how he gets a license.
我知道。
I know that.
我知道执照上写的是给奈莉·星期四之家的。
I know that the license is made out To the Nellie Thursday Home.
所以我想无论内莉·星期四在哪，那就是内莉·星期四之家，明白吗?
So I figured that wherever Nellie Thursday is, That's the Nellie Thursday Home, you see?
现在，我们要做的是。
Now, here's what we're going to do.
看,女孩。
Look, girls.
先生们要来拜访了。
Gentlemen are coming to call.
哦，他们给我们带了花!
Oh, and they're bringing us flowers!
它们必须是有价值的。
They must be valuable.
他们用枪保护他们。
They're guarding them with a gun.
把那东西拿开。
Put that thing away.
你觉得这些旧娃娃会拿杆子吗?
You think these old dolls carry rods?
你看不出来。
You can't tell.
那个安妮·奥克利女士呢?
What about that Annie Oakley dame?
把它收起来，你…好吧。
Put that away, you... All right.
好了，别忘了。
All right, now, don't forget.
帽子和"请"和"女士"都要去掉
It's off with the hat and "please" and "ma'am."
明白了吗?
You got it?
强尼，你待在这里。
Johnny, you stay here.
祝福你，善良的先生。
Bless you, kind sir.
保佑你。
Bless you.
又一天，又一美元，更少的税。
Another day, another dollar, less taxes.
谢谢你，女士。
Thank you, ma'am.
女士。
Ma'am.
我……圣诞快乐。
Me... merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐。
Merry Christmas.
不要被拒之门外。
Don't get shut out.
Everybod……圣诞快乐。
Everybod... Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐。
Merry Christmas.
哈哈!
Ho-ho!
哦，对不起，邮件是…对不起，你的钱都撒得到处都是。
Oh, I'm sorry, the post is... sorry, Your money is just spread out all over.
让我来帮你。
Let me help you with it.
找钱给你。
You get the change.
呵呵，呵呵，呵呵。
Ho-ho, ho, ho.
对不起,先生。
Sorry, sir.
你在这儿。
There you are.
先生，往锅里放点东西。
Put something in the pot, sir.
锅里有东西。
Something in the pot.
圣诞节的礼物。
Something for Christmas.
嗬，嗬，嗬。
Ho, ho, ho.
谢谢你，先生。
Thank you, sir.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
Hrrm。
Hrrm.
圣诞快乐。
Merry Christmas.
咩……女士，你要为不幸的人做点什么。
Meh... you do, ma'am, something for the less fortunate.
恐怕我没有零钱。
I'm afraid I haven't any change.
哦，没关系。
Oh, that's all right.
我来处理。
I'll handle it.
我可没想过全部拿走。
Wouldn't think of taking it all.
圣诞快乐。
Merry Christmas.
快乐……你好,威利。
Merry... hello, Willie.
你怎么认识我的?
How do you know me?
圣诞老人无所不知。
Santa Claus knows everything.
圣诞老人知道是谁抢劫了圣乔的盒子工厂。
Santa knows who knocked off that box factory at St. Joe.
圣诞老人甚至知道威利要进去调查银行的情况。
Santa even knows about Willie going In to case the bank setup.
最好在水壶里放点东西。
Better put something in the kettle.
怎么，你…如果威利没有在水壶里放点东西，圣诞老人就会停止敲钟，开始为舞蹈者、腾空者和扁平足者吹口哨。
Why, you, uh... If Willie doesn't put something in the kettle, Santa will stop ringing the bell and start Blowing the whistle for Dancer, Prancer, and Flatfoot.
圣诞快乐。
Merry Christmas.
呃，呃，呃，呃，呃。
Uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh.
祝新年快乐。
And a happy New Year.
圣诞快乐。
Merry Christmas.
嗬，嗬，嗬，嗬。
Ho, ho, ho, ho.
嗬，嗬，嗬。
Ho, ho, ho.
嗬，嗬，嗬，嗬，嗬。
Ho, ho, ho, ho, ho.
在风大的角落辛苦了一天后，没有什么比回家更好的了。
Oh, there's nothing like coming home After a hard day in a windy corner.
当然，你要和布雷尼共进晚餐。
Sure, you're going to have dinner with Brainey.
而我，却和一些熟透的海报女郎在一起。
Me, I end up with some of them overripe pin-up girls.
我本可以去华尔道夫的。
I could have gone to the Waldorf.
华尔道夫酒店吗?
The Waldorf?
你怎么敢?
How dare you?
不要不诚实。
Don't be dishonest.
这笔钱是内莉·星期四之家的。
This money belongs to the Nellie Thursday Home.
嗯?
Huh?
但是标志在哪里呢?
But where is the sign?
哦，我想是周二洗漱日。
Oh, Tuesday wash day, I guess.
嘿，门开着。
Hey, the door is open.
可能晚上出去打马球了。
Probably out playing night polo.
当你第一次按下按钮时，并没有什么东西从墙上射出来。
First time you pressed the button, And something didn't come shooting out of the wall.
嘿，那是什么?
Hey, what's that?
它只是一头牛。
It's just a cow.
牛在房子里做什么?
What's a cow doing inside a house?
米尔顿·伯利今晚上演。
Milton Berle is on tonight.
Brainey吗?
Brainey?
内莉吗?
Nellie?
大家都去哪儿了?
Where is everybody?
是啊，很好，在辛苦为他们攒钱之后。
Yeah, fine welcome after knocking ourselves Out collecting that dough for them.
哦，他们一定在附近……面团!
Oh, they must be around... the dough!
它是不见了!
It's gone!
当然，你拿着它。
Sure, you're holding it.
不,不。
No, no.
我指的是收藏。
I mean the collections.
我把它们藏在这里了。
I have them hidden in here.
我以为除了我没人知道。
I thought nobody knew about it but me.
嗯…除了我没有别人，是吗?
Uh... No one but me, huh?
牛津查理。
An Oxford Charlie.
还有谁会戴定制的14 AAAA?
Who else wears a custom-made 14 AAAA?
走吧，我们要去查理在尼亚克的家。
Come on, we're going to Charlie's place in Nyack.
帮助你自己。
Help yourself.
冰箱里有牛奶。
There's milk in the icebox.
进屋去。
Get in the house.
你想感冒吗?
You want to catch cold?
你觉得那些小盗窃犯怎么样?
How do you like those petty larceny crooks?
他们甚至偷了我们的招牌。
They even stole our sign.
天啊，真是个惊喜派对。
Boy, what a surprise party.
他们不会料到我们会来。
They'll never expect us.
请进，先生们。
Come in, gentlemen.
我在等你。
You were expected.
是的。
Yeah.
是的，我知道。
Yeah, I know.
是的。
Yeah.
是啊，他来找我要钱的时候我也是这么想的。
Yeah, that's what I figure when he comes to me for the money.
听着，你能稍等一下吗?
Look, do you mind holding on for a minute?
不，我不急。
No, I'm in no hurry.
好的，我稍等。
Yeah, I'll hold on.
好吧,孩子。
Well, Kid.
很高兴见到你。
Well, it's nice to see you.
你要什么?
What'll it be?
波旁威士忌,苏格兰威士忌吗?
Bourbon, scotch?
把我们的老女人都倒出来，快点儿。
Just pour out our old ladies and make it snappy.
啊，别紧张。
Ah, take it easy.
楼上的女士们在真正的床上非常开心。
The ladies are perfectly happy upstairs in real beds.
孩子，救救我们。
Kid, Save us.
我们的囚犯!
We're prisoners!
菲尼太太想报警，他们打了她的假牙。
Mrs. Feeney tried to call the police, And they hit her false teeth.
孩子!
Kid!
哦，我们去拿东西。
Oh, we'll get our things.
我们马上下来。
We'll be right down.
是的，快点。
Yeah, hurry up.
你知道的，小子。
You know, Kid.
你真是个天才。
You're a genius.
我以前还以为你是个小骗子呢。
Just to think that I used to have you Figured for a small-time chiseler.
而你却把百老汇所有的骗子都变成了马戏团。
And here you are making a circus out of all the con men On Broadway.
你从哪弄来的那玩意儿?
Where do you get that sucker stuff?
我们不会因为他在圣诞节坦诚相待就想骗他。
We don't figure a chance to sucker Just because he gets honest at Christmastime.
不，别转移话题。
No, don't change the subject.
我们是来找老女人的。
We're here for the old gals.
我说你们是世界上最大的傻瓜，因为你们在为奈莉·星期四之家募捐，每一分钱都进了那孩子的口袋。
I say you're the biggest suckers In the world because here you are, out collecting money For the Nellie Thursday Home, and every cent goes right Into the Kid's pocket.
真不敢相信!
I don't believe it!
我们也不知道。
We don't either.
我也是，你不能相信牛津·查理这样的人。
Neither do I. You just can't trust A character like Oxford Charlie.
同花顺，你以前为穆斯·莫兰工作。
Straight Flush, you used to work for Moose Moran.
我正在佛罗里达和慕斯通话。
I've got Moose on the phone now in Florida.
问问他为什么那小子要收一万美元。
Ask him why the Kid is collecting ten grand.
我会问他的。
I'll ask him.
喂?
Hello?
你是哪位?
Who is this?
打错了。
Wrong number.
来，给我!
Here, give me that!
别担心，小子。
Don't worry, Kid.
我们支持你。
We're with you.
你好,麋鹿。
Hello, Moose.
这是同花顺。
This is Straight Flush.
牛津查理想告诉我们"柠檬小子"是个不诚实的人。
Oxford Charlie's trying to tell us The Lemon Drop Kid is something less than on the level.
是吗?
Yeah?
嗯。
Hm.
我想我们是世界上最大的傻瓜了。
I guess we are the biggest suckers in the whole world.
我以为那小子是我的朋友。
I thought the Kid was my friend.
我就站在街角，穿着矫揉造作的衣服，摇着我的小铃铛。
And there I am, standing on the corner, wearing a hokey suit, And ringing my little bell.
嘿，那小子怎么了?
Hey, what happened to the Kid?
我知道他会怎么样。
I know what's going to happen to him.
我们去找他。
Let's find him.
现在，等一下。
Now, wait a minute.
等一下。
Wait a minute.
忘了那小子吧。
Forget about the Kid.
穆斯·莫兰会照顾他的。
Moose Moran will take care of him.
从现在起，你们为我工作。
From now on, you guys are working for me.
我们会从这笔生意中赚到每一分钱。
We'll squeeze every dime out of this racket.
每个人都有很大的分成。
And there'll be a big fat cut for everybody.
孩子!
Kid!
孩子，我觉得你是世上最卑微的…现在,Brainey。
Kid, I think that you are the lowest thing... Now, Brainey.
不要急于下结论。
Don't jump to conclusions.
我可以解释一切。
I can explain everything.
从我第一次见到你，你就一直在解释肮脏的把戏。
You've been explaining dirty tricks Since the first time I met you.
我得筹集一万美元。
Well, I had to raise ten grand.
你想让我被杀吗?
Did you want me to get killed?
这是你想到的最好的主意!
That's the best idea you ever had!
你怎么能这么卑鄙到…我不知道那些老娃娃会这么受欢迎。
How can you be so low as to, uh... I didn't realize the old dolls would take it so big.
至少，他们还会有回报。
At least, they're going to be around for the payoff.
在平安夜，慕斯·莫兰会给我打上"付清"的标记
On Christmas Eve, Moose Moran is going To mark me "paid in full."
那是八天假。
That's eight days off.
你想让我怎么做?
What do you expect me to do?
从牛津·查理这样的流氓那里偷钱?
Steal the money back from a hoodlum like Oxford Charlie?
为什么不呢?
Why not?
至少百老汇会有人为你流泪。
Then at least, somebody around Broadway Might shed a tear for you.
我再也不会这么做了。
That's more than I'll ever do again.
这个戒指多少钱?
How much on this ring?
你的结婚戒指?
Your wedding ring?
很抱歉，内莉，我的婚戒太多了。
I'm sorry, Nellie, but I'm loaded up with wedding rings.
哦,鲁珀特。
Oh, Rupert.
你得给我点线索。
You got to give me something on it.
是为今晚的家庭聚会准备的。
It's for, uh, well, tonight's sort of a family reunion.
好的。
OK.
把它脱下来。
Take it off.
我来看看。
I'll have a look.
很久没戒了。
Haven't had it off a long time.
你们女人总是匆匆忙忙的。
You women are always in such a rush.
你想做什么?
What are you trying to do?
抢劫她的珠宝?
Heist her jewelry?
孩子，我的麻烦够多了。
Kid, I got enough trouble.
你现在想从我这里得到什么?
What do you want from me now?
听着，内莉，一群好人为你筹了很多钱。
Look, Nellie, a bunch of swell guys collected a lot of money For you.
我不会让一个骗子，一个骗子，和一个面包屑把事情搞糟。
I'm not going to let a cheat, chiseler, And a crumb gum up the worse.
你是说牛津查理吧。
You mean Oxford Charlie.
谁?
Who?
是的。
Yeah.
你是怎么从他家逃出来的?
Say, how did you get out of his place?
其他的娃娃和布雷尼呢?
Where are the other dolls and Brainey?
还在尼亚克。
Still in Nyack.
我等待机会，然后偷偷溜了出去。
I waited for my chance, and then I sneaked out.
好吧，如果你能溜出去，我也能溜进去。
Yeah, well, if you can sneak out, I can sneak in.
我要去拿那些属于你和其他旧娃娃的钱。
I'm going to get that money that belongs To you and the other old dolls.
孩子，别试。
Kid, don't try it.
你不会成功的。
You'll never make it.
查理那儿到处都是警卫。
Why, Charlie's got guards all over there.
和他……看，看，内莉。
And he's... Look, look, Nellie.
我有一个角度。
I've got an angle.
现在，再听我说一次。
Now, listen to me, just once more.
我要你把所有男孩都召集起来。
I want you to round up all the boys.
带他们去法院。
Take them to the courthouse.
联系一下法官。
Get a hold of the judge.
和…
And...
一步……别挡我的路!
Step... get out of my way!
你好,首席。
Hello, Chief.
一共95美分。
That'll be 95 cents.
哦,是的。
Oh, yeah.
95美分和1美元给你自己。
95 cents and a dollar for yourself.
哦，不，妈妈。
Oh, no, mother.
你不用给我小费。
You don't have to tip me.
真的吗?
Really?
嗯,在这里。
Well, here.
来支雪茄。
Have a cigar.
梦想不需要花费一分钱。
It doesn't cost a dime to dream.
我们会在墙上挂满美钞。
We'll line our walls with dollar bills.
是吗?
Yeah?
我是个没饭吃的可怜老太太，好心的先生。
I'm a poor old lady who haven't got to eat, Kind sir.
我听说这是一个老太太的家…当然了。
And I heard this was an old lady's home... Sure it is.
但我们的耳朵都在老娃娃的嘴里了。
But we're up to our ears in old dolls' mouths.
但我无处可去。
Oh, but I have no place to go.
我这辈子都得省吃俭用来养孩子。
All my life, I've had to scrimp and save To support my children.
我日复一日地在火炉上做饭，一直缝到眼睛发麻。
I've sewed till my eyes burned, cooked over a hot stove day After day.
我甚至还得把地板拿去洗。
I even have to take in floors to wash.
对不起，老娃娃。
Sorry, old doll.
不行。
No dice.
哦，拜托，先生。
Oh, please, sir.
如果你把我拒之门外，我将无处可去，只能去找当局。
If you turn me away, I'll have no place To go except to the authorities.
呃，等等，女士。
Eh, uh, hold it, ma'am.
嗯，请进。
Eh, come right in.
我会跟老板说的。
I'll talk to the boss.
既然你是个没饭吃的可怜老太太，也许他会改变我的想法。
Seeing as you're a poor old lady who hasn't got to eat, Maybe he'll change my mind.
在这儿等着，我为你美言几句。
Wait here while I put in a kind word for you.
嗯嗯。
Mm-hm.
那是个老太太?
That's an old lady?
头儿，她又想从窗户逃出去了。
Boss, she was trying to get out the window again.
内莉的消失了。
Nellie's disappeared.
必须有人找到她。
And somebody's got to find her.
布雷尼，我警告过你要守规矩，否则我就要让孩子们…我会想尽一切办法离开这里。
Brainey, I warned you to stay in line, Or I'm going to have the boys... I'll get out of here any way I can.
那好吧。
All right then.
带她回房间去。
Take her back to her room.
跟着她，直到把他们都搬走为止。
And stick with her until it's time to move them all out.
外面那个新的旧娃娃呢?
And what about the new old doll outside?
好吧，再喝几小时也无妨。
Well, one more for a couple of hours won't hurt anything.
而且，我们不能让她去报警。
Besides, we can't have her going to the police.
好吧，带她进来。
All right, show her in.
这就是她，老板。
This is her, boss.
太太比斯利。
Mrs. Beasley.
赫伯特·比斯利夫人。
Mrs. Herbert Beasley.
欢迎来到我们家，比斯利夫人。
Well, welcome to our home, Mrs. Beasley.
你知道吗，你正好赶上搬到我们的新地方。
You know, you're just in time to move to our new location.
你看，其他女孩会一直待在这房子里直到圣诞节。
See, the other girls are just going to stay in this house Until Christmastime.
然后他们搬到一个真正的豪宅。
Then they move to a real mansion.
大得像赌场。
Big as a casino.
哦，听起来太棒了!
Oh, that sounds wonderful!
这意味着你接受我为客人了吗?
Does it mean that you accept me as a guest?
嗯嗯。
Mm-hm.
我高兴得都想哭了。
Oh, I'm so happy, I could cry.
好吧，好吧。
All right, all right.
这是……
That's...
-我的药。-我的药。
- My medicine. - My medicine.
哦。
Oh.
马克西，把她和其他漂亮的老太太带进去，好吗?
Hey, Maxie, take her in with the other nice old ladies, Will you?
我永远不会忘记你的。
Oh, I'll never forget you for this.
你是个好人。
You're a good man.
你是个很好的人。
You're a very good man.
啊，算了吧。
Ah, forget it.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
嘿，好老太太!
Hey, nice old lady!
你拿错包了。
You've got the wrong bag.
哦，我的天哪!
Oh, my goodness!
我确实犯了个错误。
I did make a mistake.
笨拙的我。
Clumsy me.
很重，不是吗?
Heavy, isn't it?
你在用什么编织?
What are you knitting with?
钢丝绒?
Steel wool?
嗯。
Hm.
如果我能买得起新眼镜，我就…梦想不需要花费一分钱……
If I could only afford some new glasses, I... It doesn't cost a dime to dream...
女士们，这位是俱乐部的新成员，比斯利夫人。
Ladies, meet a new member of the club, Mrs. Beasley.
你好，比斯利夫人。
How do you do, Mrs. Beasley?
我知道和你们这些好人在一起我会很快乐的。
I know I'm going to be Happy with all you nice people.
很高兴你能来。
So nice to have you.
嗯，可怜的孩子。
Hm, you poor dear.
坐在这里。
Sit here.
哦，谢谢。
Oh, thank you.
嗯嗯。
Mm-hm.
女士们，这不是一个可爱的家吗?
Isn't this a lovely home, ladies?
我们不想让你失望，比斯利夫人。
We hate to disillusion you, Mrs. Beasley.
那是个又大又硬的老监狱。
It's a great, big, hard old jail.
监狱吗?
Jail?
亲爱的我!
Dear me!
但是典狱长……呃，那个主管看起来是个不错的人。
But the warden... uh, the superintendent Seem like such a nice one.
那不是主管。
That's not the superintendent.
他是牛津查理，那个敲诈犯。
He's Oxford Charlie, the racketeer.
恐怖!
Horrors!
他跟柠檬小子一样是个大流氓。
He's as big a hoodlum as The Lemon Drop Kid.
嗯。
Hm.
亲爱的，你在忙什么呢?
What are you working on, dear?
哦，哈哈。
Oh, ha, ha.
在Gen之后。
Uh, after Gen.
卡斯特被杀了，比斯利先生坚持要我一直带着他的手枪。
Custer was massacred, Mr. Beasley Insisted I carry his pistol at all times.
印度人，你知道的。
Indians, you know.
嗯。
Hm.
讨厌的红人队。
Pesky redskins.
你到底在织什么?
What in the world are you knitting?
拖把。
Uh, a mop.
到处都找不到。
Hard to get them anywhere.
它们和我的阿盖尔磨砂桶很搭。
And they go so well with my Argyle scrub bucket.
你不觉得大一点的腰带，在我们这个年纪会更明智吗?
Eh, don't you think a larger sized girdle would, uh, Be much more sensible at our age?
我把它拿得很小。
I take it small.
总是有。
Always have.
亲爱的比斯利先生，他为我沙漏般的身材感到骄傲。
Dear Mr. Beasley, he was so proud of my hourglass figure.
亲爱的，你的身材还是那么沙漏。
You still have your hourglass figure, dear.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
但是大部分沙子都沉到了海底。
But most of the sand has gone to the bottom.
是的。
Yes.
好了，老女孩们。
There we go, old girls.
大家准备好。
Everybody get ready.
我们要搬出去。
We're moving out.
老花店又要送货了。
The Old Flower Shoppe is going to make another delivery.
来吧。
Come on.
这太离谱了!
This is outrageous!
那是一次短暂的拜访，不是吗?
That was a short visit, wasn't it?
我的纱!
My yarn!
哦,是的。
Oh, yes.
嗯嗯。
Mm-hm.
哦!
Oh!
来吧，亲爱的。
Come along, dear.
来了,来了。
Coming, coming.
我的外套。
My coat.
我的外套!
My coat!
他们在外面的卡车里。
They're out in the truck.
你的狗!
You dog!
来吧，老娃娃!
Come on, old doll!
来了,来了。
Coming, coming.
你知道你在干什么吗?
What do you think you're doing?
我以为你们这些漂亮的旧娃娃都没了。
I thought all you nice old dolls had left.
我不是一个可爱的老娃娃。
I'm not a nice old doll.
我不会走的。
And I'm not leaving.
我没有枪!
And I haven't got a gun!
柠檬滴小孩!
The Lemon Drop Kid!
小心!
Watch out!
哦,不!
Oh, no!
关税…
Impost...
噢!
Ow!
喂!
Ho!
上帝!
God!
啊!
Ugh!
嘿!
Hey!
我的脚!
My foot!
在哪里…哦!
Where is the... oh!
不!
No!
哦，呃，打扰一下，老板。
Oh, uh, excuse me, boss.
停止它!
Stop it!
你弄疼我了!放开!
You're hurting me! Let go!
你弄皱我的裙子了!
You're wrinkling my dress!
你疯了!
You're mad!
他弄得我屁股都快断了!
He's busting my hip!
救救我!
Someone save me!
救我!
Save me!
给我!
Give me that!
啊!
Ugh!
是你叫我的，老大?
You called me, boss?
年轻人，给我让开!
Young man, get out of my way!
她是柠檬娃娃!
She's the Lemon Drop Kid!
诱饵!
Stool pigeon!
为什么,你!
Why, you!
不!
No!
你用这个不会伤害任何女士的!
You wouldn't hurt no lady with that!
他做到了。
He did.
得到她!
Get her!
他拿了我的钱!
He's got my money!
那是柠檬娃娃。
That's the Lemon Drop Kid.
我们去抓他!
Let's get him!
往那边走!
Go around that way!
他不能穿着这些裙子跑!
He can't run in those skirts!
女士，我是迪克·丹尼尔斯。
Ma'am, Dick Daniels.
人巡逻。
People Patrol.
我能为您效劳吗?
May I be of service?
好的，谢谢你。
Well, thank you.
哈里特·比斯利，驿马快信。
Harriet Beasley, Pony Express.
邮件一定能到达。
The mail must go through.
谢谢你！
Thank you!
哦!
Oops!
小心!
Watch out!
来吧。
Come on.
把它弄出去。
Get it out of here.
备份。
Back it up.
哇!
Whoa!
的借口!
Excuse!
不好意思。
Oops, pardon me.
对不起，我的房间着火了。
Pardon me, my room's on fire.
哎呀!
Whoops!
你没事吧，妈妈?
You all right, mother?
妈妈吗?
Mother?
我还没结婚呢。
I'm not even married.
你看到我看到的了吗?
Did you see what I saw?
是的，我看到她了。
Yeah, I saw her.
你看见一位老太太了吗?
Did you see an old lady?
是的，她在里面，警官。
Yes, she's in there, Officer.
是吗?
Yeah?
她活不了多久了。
Not for long, she ain't.
你看到里面有个老太太吗?
Did you see an old lady in there?
一个老太太?
An old lady?
啊，哈哈，很有趣。
Ah, ha-ha, very funny.
我听到了。
I heard it.
我看见的那个老太太是谁?
Who was that old lady I saw?
哈哈，很好。
Ha-ha, very good.
我是毛巾公司的。
I'm with the towel company.
Hrrm。
Hrrm.
我在佛罗里达听到的关于旧娃娃之家的事是怎么回事?
What's this I hear in Florida about an old dolls' home?
这是那小子的主意。
It was the Kid's idea.
我说他疯了，但他就是这么筹到钱的。
I told him he was crazy, but that's How he figured to raise the money.
我不想让旧娃娃或其他任何人在这里鬼混。
I don't want old dolls or anybody else Fooling around here.
纽约警察会因为我又开了这家店而把我绞死的。
The New York cops would love to hang one On me for opening this place again.
我们抓住那小子，然后把他关起来。
We collect on the Kid, and then lock it up tight.
嗨,孩子。
Hi, Kid.
山姆告诉我你筹到了一万美元。
Sam tells me you raised the ten grand.
这很好。
That's good.
是的。
Yeah.
我都帮你算好了。
I got it all counted out for you.
给你，一万英镑。
Here you are, ten thousand even.
快到圣诞节了，再过十五分钟就到了。
Say, it's almost Christmas, just fifteen minutes more.
难道你不愿意给我五千块来展示你的圣诞精神吗?
Wouldn't you like to settle for five thousand just To show your Christmas spirit, huh?
丫……7500年?
Would ya... 75 hundred?
没有精神，是吧?
No spirit, huh?
你可以忘了我的礼物。
You can forget my presents.
你不必…好吧，一万偶数。
You don't have to... OK, ten thousand even.
全额支付。
Paid in full.
穆斯，你好。
Well, Moose, hello.
你什么时候进城的?
When did you hit town?
刚到，查理。
Just arrived, Charlie.
有些收集工作要做。
Had some collecting to do.
你这个叛徒。
Oh, you rat.
那是我的钱袋。
That's my money bag.
我的一万六千呢?
Where's my 16 grand?
哦，好吧，在这儿。
Oh, well, here it is.
我只是借来的。
I just borrowed it.
你在这儿。
There you are.
现在，你得到了回报。
Now, you're paid off.
你得到了回报。
And you're paid off.
每个人都很开心。
And everybody's happy.
让我们握握手，祝彼此圣诞快乐，好吗?
Let's shake hands and wish each other a Merry Christmas, huh?
等一下。
Just a minute.
你欠我一万块钱。
You owe me ten grand.
哦，是的，你就是那个人。
Oh, yeah, you're the one.
你在这儿。
There you are.
你不需要算出来。
You don't have to work it out.
我做了我该做的。
I've done my share.
你为什么要凿……山姆!
Why you chiseling... Sam!
我们不能在这里赌博!
We can't have gambling here!
萨姆，去拿开关!
Get that switch, Sam!
去拿开关!
Get the switch!
呃，这样换一下怎么样?
Ho, how's that for a switch?
走吧!
Go!
让我们活得轻松一点吧，伙计们。
Let's live a little, folks.
萨利，他们胆子更大。
Solly, they're bolder.
-带他过去。-让我揍他!
- Get him there. - Let me just beat him!
让我……下注吧!
Let me... Place your bets!
呆在那里。
Stay there.
抓住你的马鞍。
Hold your saddle.
我不会让他们伤害你的。
I won't let them hurt you.
来吧，萨利。
Come on, Solly.
八是赢家!
Eight's the winner!
这是被陷害的。
This thing's a frame-up.
你怎么猜到的?
How'd you guess?
根据我的日程安排，警察来了。
And according to my schedule, here come the police.
这个地方被洗劫了!
The joint is raided!
先生，你看到我的自行车了吗?
Please, sir, did you see my bicycle?
我会给你买一个新的。来吧，伙计们!
I'll buy you a new one. Come on, men!
来吧，孩子们。
Come on, boys.
就是它了!
This is it!
这是突袭!
This is a raid!
好吧,男孩。
OK, boys.
站在原地!
Stand where you are!
哦，这太棒了。
Oh, this is great.
我让你当船长。
I'll make you a captain.
我是船长。
I am a captain.
好的，海军上将。
OK, an admiral.
慕斯，你又因为开赌场被捕了。
Moose, you're under arrest for running a gambling joint again.
这不是赌博场所。
This isn't a gambling joint.
这是一个…这是一个旧娃娃之家。
It's a... it's an old dolls' home.
你在开玩笑吗?
Are you kidding?
把它们拿出来。
Take them out.
现在，稍等一下!
Now, just a minute!
什么……你以为你要去哪里?
What... Where do you think you're going?
好吧，我要走了。
Well, I'm getting out of here.
这地方不是我的。
I don't own this place.
你不能把任何罪名栽赃给我。
You can't pin anything on me.
查理，我们从一开始就在关注你的慈善活动。
Charlie, we've been watching your charity racket From the beginning.
这笔钱是为奈莉·星期四之家筹集的。
This money was collected for the Nellie Thursday Home.
这就是它的发展方向。
And that's where it's going.
逮捕他，警官。
Arrest him, Officer.
哦，现在有人叫我…嘿，放开我的脚!
Oh, now, somebody call my... hey, let go of my feet!
我会盯着你的，米尔本先生。
And I'm going to keep an eye on you, Mr. Milburn.
你不必这么做，法官。
You won't have to, Judge.
我要改过自新。
I'm turning over a new leaf.
我再也不会被抓住了。
I'll never be caught again.
说，谢谢你所做的一切，法官。
Say, thanks for everything, Judge.
如果你想赢，打给我。
If you ever want a winner, call me.
女士们先生们还有你们所有人，你们太棒了!
Everybody, ladies and gentlemen and all the rest of you, You were great!
内莉，成功了。
Nellie, it worked.
好吗?
Well?
内莉!
Nellie!
你丈夫，亨利，他要来了。
Your husband, Henry, he's a-coming.
他只是从雕像旁边经过!
He's a-just a-passing the statue!
哦，嗬嗬，就是这个了，各位!
Oh, ho-ho, this is it, everybody!
古巴，把开关拉开，把桌子搬走。
Goomba, pull the switches and get rid of the tables.
-是的。-来吧。
- Yeah. - Come on.
-是的。-来吧。布雷尼，别走开。
- Yeah. - Come on. Brainey, don't go away.
布雷尼，别走开。
Brainey, don't go away.
我想和你谈谈。
I want to talk to you.
内莉。
Nellie.
欢迎回家，亨利。
Welcome home, Henry.
哦。
Aw.
你看起来很漂亮，内莉。
You look very pretty, Nellie.
很高兴见到你，亨利。
It's nice to see you, Henry.
亨利，这是柠檬小子。
Henry, this is the Lemon Drop Kid.
他要为这一切负责。
He's responsible for all this.
谢谢你,孩子。
Thanks, Kid.
哦，这是可扣除的。
Oh, it's deductible.
进来吧，汉克。
Come on in, Hank.
这是我们的贵宾，亨利·里根夫妇。
Here's our guests of honor, Mr. And Mrs. Henry Regan.
快12点了。
It's almost 12 o'clock.
该上冰淇淋了。
Time to serve the ice cream.
我去拿餐巾纸和盘子。
I'll get the napkins and the dishes.
你真棒。
Goody for you.
这是你的派对，内莉。
It's your party, Nellie.
过来切蛋糕。
Come and cut the cake.
银器在哪里?
Where is the silverware?
外科医生山姆说它在保险箱里。
Sam the Surgeon said it was in the safe.
我们怎么把它弄出来?
How do we get it out?
从保险柜里出来?
Out of the safe?
是啊，我们怎么把它从保险箱里拿出来?
Yeah, how do we get it out of the safe?
保险箱里。
The safe.
哦,不。
Oh, no.
不是我。
Not me.
但这是内奸，亨利。
But it's an inside job, Henry.
什么是非法的。
Nothing illegal.
算是客人拍的。
Sort of a guest shot.
我刚因为非法开锁坐了二十年牢。
I just did twenty years for safe cracking.
所以没有银制餐具我们就不能供应冰淇淋。
So we can't serve the ice cream without the silverware.
这一切都是为了纪念你。
And the whole thing is in your honor.
再说了，你也不能突然停止。
Besides, you can't stop all of a sudden.
你必须逐渐减少。
You have to taper off.
好吧，我得带上我的纪念品。
Well, uh, I'll have to take my keepsakes with me.
哦，东西在这儿，哈?
Oh, the stuff is here, ha?
美妙的,亨利。
Wonderful, Henry.
祝你好运。
Good luck.
对不起，内莉。
Excuse me a minute, Nellie.
你现在在忙什么?
What are you up to now?
我在这里，你在那里。
Oh, I'm up to here, you're up to there.
多好的赌注啊?
What a parlay, huh?
拿着电话。
Hold the phone.
你眼睛里有固定种族的表情。
You've got that fixed race look in your eye.
你不觉得这很可爱吗?
Don't you see that's lovely?
天啊，我可以自由结婚了。
God, I'm free to get married.
可怜的小娃娃，你等了太久了。
Oh, you poor little doll, you've been waiting so long.
但对你来说是值得的。
But it was worth it to you.
现在，你难倒我了。
Now, you got me.
但是我们负担不起。
But we can't afford it.
我最近没有工作。
I haven't been working lately.
放松。
Relax.
我都计划好了。
I have everything planned.
但是我们要用什么来赚钱呢?
But what are we going to use for money?
别担心，亲爱的。
Don't worry, honey.
我要把银器当掉。
I'll hock the silverware.
安静,Crosby
Quiet, Crosby.